本字幕由高清电台整理发布，更多高清电影请访问
https://gaoqing.fm
（有趣的
(INTRIGUING
西洋音樂演奏）
WESTERN MUSIC PLAYING)
（音樂漸強、漸弱）
(MUSIC CRESCENDOES, FADES)
（音樂脈衝）
(MUSIC PULSES)
（水手們講德語）
(SAILORS SPEAKING GERMAN)
（船長用德語）
(CAPTAIN IN GERMAN)
男士：（用英語）呃，瑞典。
MAN: (IN ENGLISH) Uh, Sweden.
（在德國）
(IN GERMAN)
男：（英語）
MAN: (IN ENGLISH)
我是...我是...瑞典人
I'm... I'm... Swedish
但我會說一點英語。
but I speak a little English.
我們要上船了。
We're coming on board.
（水手們用德語喊叫）
(SAILORS SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
（船長用德語點菜）
(CAPTAIN ORDERING IN GERMAN)
（英語）歡迎大家。
(IN ENGLISH) All are welcome.
歡迎大家。
All are welcome.
即使是小個子。
Even the little one.
他也可以來。
He can come too.
歡迎。
Welcome.
（懸疑的音樂播放）
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
你為什麼在這？
Why are you here?
只是一個小小的航海假期。
Just a little sailing holiday.
一次快樂的男孩之旅。
A jolly boys trip.
把你的手拿開。
Take your hands off.
文件？
Papers?
護照？
Passport?
（咕嚕聲）給你。
(GRUNTS) Here you go.
船上還有其他人嗎？
Any other people on the boat?
只有我們倆。
Just the two of us.
（在德國）
(IN GERMAN)
不。
Nein.
（船長講話）
(CAPTAIN SPEAKING)
（英語）來來來，
(IN ENGLISH) Come, come,
我們有很多吃的...
we have lots to eat...
把你的髒手拿開！
Take your dirty hands off me!
-（水手們用德語喊叫）
- (SAILORS SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
-（槍待發）
- (GUNS COCKING)
船長：（用英語）退後！
CAPTAIN: (IN ENGLISH) Back off!
你呢，
And you,
把你的手舉到空中！
put your hands in the air!
（笑）
(LAUGHING)
哦！ （笑）
Ooh! (LAUGHING)
你現在有麻煩了！
You're in trouble now!
你本來就是個頑皮的孩子！
You've been a naughty boy!
我給你100法郎
I'll give you 100 francs
射殺他。
to shoot him.
別開槍打我！
Don't shoot me!
（兩人都繼續笑）
(BOTH CONTINUE LAUGHING)
他討厭德國人。
He hates Germans.
你真的應該開槍打死他。
You should really shoot him.
我……對不起。
I... I'm sorry.
你很可怕。
You are very scary.
男人：讓他走木板。
MAN: Make him walk the plank.
他喜歡木頭。
He loves wood.
（兩人都繼續笑）
(BOTH CONTINUE LAUGHING)
骯髒的喝醉的動物！
Dirty drunken animal!
被指控有罪。
Guilty as charged.
（兩人都笑）
(BOTH LAUGHING)
（德語）
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
- （水手們說德語）
- (SAILORS SPEAKING GERMAN)
-（抽屜嘎嘎聲）
- (DRAWER RATTLES)
（英語）我總是採取
(IN ENGLISH) I always take
一罐煤油
a can of kerosene
只是為了
for just
這些場合。
these sort of occasions.
（吸氣）
(INHALES)
有一陣子了，
It's been a while,
但最後一次
but the last time
有人嘲笑我
someone laughed at me
當我登上他們的船時
when I boarded their vessel,
我給了他們選擇。
I gave them the choice.
要麼游到岸邊
Either swim to shore
或者抓住機會
or take their chances
在一艘燃燒的船上。
on a burning ship.
（液體澆注）
(LIQUID POURING)
漢斯和我想知道
Hans and I wondered
他們會選擇哪個選項，
which option they'd choose,
水死或火死。
death by water or death by fire.
奇怪的是，他們都選擇了。
Oddly, they chose both.
（德語）
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
（懸疑音樂繼續）
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC CONTINUES)
（英語）他們等待著
(IN ENGLISH) They waited
直到最後一刻，
until the very last moment,
直到頭髮著火，
until their hair was on fire,
和他們起泡的皮膚
and their blistered skin
從他們的手指上剝落，
peeled from their fingers,
在他們沉浸之前
before they immersed
自己在水中
themselves in water
在徒勞的希望中
in the vain hope
到達岸邊。
of reaching shore.
其中之一
One of them
立即沉沒並滅亡。
sank immediately and perished.
但令我們驚訝的是，
But to our amazement,
大的那個，
the big one,
他表現出了偉大的精神。
he showed great spirit.
儘管困難重重......
In spite of all the odds...
（在德國）
(IN GERMAN)
...他煞費苦心
...he painstakingly
成功到達岸邊。
made it to shore.
我們跟著他並為他加油
We followed and cheered him on
並得到獎勵
and rewarded
這一令人印象深刻的成就
this impressive achievement
用子彈
with a bullet
到他的後腦勺。
to the back of his head.
這不是很有趣嗎？
Isn't that funny?
你為什麼不笑？
Why aren't you laughing?
-（槍聲安靜）
- (GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
-（水手們咕噥、尖叫）
- (SAILORS GRUNT, SCREAM)
（水手們大聲叫嚷）
(SAILORS CLAMORING)
-（猛擊）
- (SLASHING)
-（喘氣）
- (GASPS)
（有趣的西方音樂演奏）
(AMUSING WESTERN MUSIC PLAYING)
-（男人咕噥）
- (MAN GRUNTS)
-（槍聲安靜）
- (GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
-（咕嚕聲）
- (GRUNTS)
- （水手 1 用德語喊叫）
- (SAILOR 1 SHOUTS IN GERMAN)
-（槍聲安靜）
- (GUN FIRES QUIETLY)
-（水手 2 尖叫）
- (SAILOR 2 YELPS)
-（水手 3 咕嚕聲）
- (SAILOR 3 GRUNTS)
-（水手們用德語喊叫）
- (SAILORS SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
（水手 4 尖叫）
(SAILOR 4 SCREAMS)
-（槍聲安靜）
- (GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
-（水手們咕噥著）
- (SAILORS GRUNTING)
-（槍聲安靜）
- (GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
-（水手 5 喘息）
- (SAILOR 5 GASPS)
-（嘆氣）
- (SIGHS)
-（水手 6 尖叫）
- (SAILOR 6 YELPS)
（呻吟）
(GROANING)
-（咆哮）
- (GROWLS)
-（水手 7 呻吟）
- (SAILOR 7 GROANS)
（有趣
(AMUSING
西方音樂繼續）
WESTERN MUSIC CONTINUES)
幹得好，拉森。
Nice work, Lassen.
還有更多
There's more
那是從哪裡來的。
where that came from.
是的。
Yes.
（拉森呻吟聲）
(LASSEN GROANS)
（拉森咕噥）
(LASSEN GRUNTS)
啊...
Ah...
不確定它是否有效，拉森。
Not sure it's working, Lassen.
船長
The captain
看起來比較激動。
looks rather agitated.
他們帶著槍
They're bringing their guns
忍受忍受。
to bear.
（導彈發射）
(MISSILE FIRES)
他們會找到自己的範圍
They'll find their range
很快，先生。
soon, sir.
弗雷迪，我們應該擔心嗎？
Freddy, should we be worried?
哦，我不這麼認為，先生。
Oh, I don't think so, sir.
這是一個相當大的炸藥
It's a rather large explosive,
所以我設置了一個相當大的保險絲。
so I set a rather large fuse.
我找到了外面
I located the outside
化妝間的，
of the powder room,
所以當它爆炸時
so when it goes bang,
它真的應該爆炸。
it really should go bang.
（導彈發射）
(MISSILE FIRES)
（爆炸）
(EXPLOSION)
靠近一點...
Closer...
現在應該是任何時候了，夥計們。
Should be any second now, chaps.
（水手們在遠處喊叫）
(SAILORS CLAMORING IN DISTANCE)
弗雷迪？
Freddy?
（爆炸聲）
(EXPLOSION BOOMING)
幹得好，弗雷德裡克。
Good work, Frederick.
謝謝你，船長。
Thank you, Captain.
現在，只要有機會你可以告訴我們
Now, any chance you can tell us
我們在這裡做什麼，先生？
what we're doing here, sir?
（音樂漸弱）
(MUSIC FADES)
（投影儀點擊）
(PROJECTOR CLICKING)
（歡快的管絃樂演奏）
(JOLLY ORCHESTRAL MUSIC PLAYING)
新聞播音員：（在投影儀上）
NEWSREADER: (ON PROJECTOR)
歐洲戰爭愈演愈烈
The war in Europe rages on
作為希特勒和他的納粹部落
as Hitler and his Nazi horde
掃除他們路上的一切。
sweep aside all in their path.
波蘭、比利時，現在是法國
Poland, Belgium and now France
都倒下了
have all fallen
希特勒的法西斯政權，
to Hitler's fascist regime,
離開英國
leaving Britain
抱著最後的希望
holding up the final hopes
解放
of liberation
對於整個歐洲。
for all of Europe.
所以，來吧，布萊蒂，
So, come on, Blighty,
準備好戰鬥吧。
get ready for a fighty.
但我們無法單獨做到這一點。
But we cannot do it alone.
還有任何希望
And any hope
為了我們的美國兄弟
for our American brothers
加入我們
to join us
來自大西洋彼岸
from across the Atlantic
仍然沮喪
remains frustrated
德國的秘密武器，
by Germany's secret weapon,
U型潛艇。
the U-boat.
這些致命的小型潛艇
These deadly little submarines
隨意狩獵
hunt at will
在北大西洋。
in the North Atlantic.
不可探測，U 型潛艇
Undetectable, the U-boat
不分青紅皂白地擊沉船隻，
sinks ships indiscriminately,
是否攜帶
whether carrying
彈藥、給養
munitions, provisions
或平民前往
or civilians heading
來自我們的同伴
from our companions
穿過池塘。
across the pond.
只要有潛艇
So long as the U-boats
統治大西洋，
rule the Atlantic,
這仍然是不可能的
it remains impossible
為了美國勇敢的軍隊
for America's brave troops
到達我們的海岸。
to reach our shores.
英國會被迫嗎
Will Britain be forced
安撫希特勒的計劃
to appease Hitler's plans
否則將面臨毀滅
or face devastation
從他的進攻中？
from his offensive?
倫敦燃燒
London burns
她的海洋變成紅色，
and her seas run red,
如來自上方的炸彈
as bombs from above
和來自下方的魚雷
and torpedoes from below
碾壓英國人。
grind the Brits down.
並且沒有防禦
And with no defense
對抗這些致命的潛艇，
against these lethal U-boats,
看來所有的希望都破滅了
it appears all hope may be lost
為了歐洲的和平。
for peace in Europe.
-（音樂停止）
- (MUSIC STOPS)
-（投影儀點擊聲）
- (PROJECTOR CLICKS)
德國人切斷了
The Germans cut off
我們的潛艇供應鏈，
our supply chain with U-boats,
我們切斷供應鏈
we cut off the supply chain
到U型潛艇。
to the U-boats.
通過我們的情報人員，
Through our intelligence agents,
我們找到了辦法。
we've found a way.
（有趣的西部片
(INTRIGUING WESTERN
音樂播放）
MUSIC PLAYING)
整個
The entire
保養、修理、
servicing, repairing,
並重新武裝
and rearming
希特勒的
of Hitler's
大西洋U型潛艇艦隊...
Atlantic U-boat fleet...
已運行
is operated
由兩艘納粹拖船......
by two Nazi tug boats...
和一艘意大利補給船
and an Italian supply ship
在費爾南多·波。
in Fernando Po.
我需要願意的男人
I need men who are willing
去擊沉那些船。
to go and sink those ships.
我們為什麼不直接
Why don't we just
空襲費爾南多·波
air-raid Fernando Po
並擊沉船隻？
and sink the ships?
（呼氣）
(EXHALES)
因為狡猾的德國人，
Because crafty Germans,
作為狡猾的德國人，
being crafty Germans,
已經給自己定位了
have positioned themselves
在西班牙殖民地。
in a Spanish colony.
費爾南多·波
Fernando Po
是中立領土。
is neutral territory.
如果我們攻擊那個殖民地，
If we attack that colony,
歐洲其他未佔領地區
the rest of unoccupied Europe
將加入納粹，
will join the Nazis,
而且這只是
and it's only
時間問題
a question of time
在我們找到自己之前
before we find ourselves
煎大粉紅香腸
frying big pink sausages
只穿皮短褲。
wearing nothing but lederhosen.
希特勒不是
Hitler is not
遵守遊戲規則
playing by the rules
我們也不是。
and neither are we.
這當然會是
This will of course be
未經批准的、
an unsanctioned,
未經授權的
unauthorized
和非官方任務。
and unofficial mission.
如果他們被抓獲
If they're captured
由英國人，
by the British,
他們將被投入監獄。
they'll be thrown in jail.
但如果納粹找到他們...
But if the Nazis find them...
這是酷刑和死亡。
it's torture and death.
男士：有點爭議，
MAN: Somewhat contentiously,
我可能只有這個男人，
I may have just the man,
但相當不方便，
but rather inconveniently,
他目前被監禁
he's currently incarcerated
遵照陛下的意願。
at His Majesty's pleasure.
我們可能不喜歡他的態度，
We may not like his attitude,
但他很大膽，他是個殺手
but he's bold, he's a killer,
和男人們
and the men
會跟隨他到任何地方。
will follow him anywhere.
我們確定這是個好主意嗎？
Are we sure this is a good idea?
我們當然不是。
Of course we're not.
但我們很絕望。
But we're desperate.
- 把他送進來。
- Send him in.
-（門打開）
- (DOOR OPENS)
中士：前進！
SERGEANT: Forward!
-（腳步聲接近）
- (FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
-（鏈條叮噹響）
- (CHAINS CLINKING)
中士：站在那裡，少校。
SERGEANT: Stand there, Major.
（有趣的音樂繼續）
(INTRIGUING MUSIC CONTINUES)
男：謝謝你，中士。
MAN: Thank you, Sergeant.
格斯·馬奇-菲利普斯，
Gus March-Phillips,
這是中尉……
this is Lieutenant Commander...
弗萊明.伊恩·弗萊明.
Fleming. Ian Fleming.
他以前是
He used to be
在海軍情報局，
at Naval Intelligence,
現在他為我工作。
now he works for me.
我為什麼在這裡，M？
Why am I here, M?
我有一個使命
I have a mission
我要你來領導。
I want you to lead.
你為什麼問我，M？
Why are you asking me, M?
幫助自己
Help yourself
喝杯茶，少校。
to a cup of tea, Major.
（格斯清嗓子）
(GUS CLEARS THROAT)
我們都知道我是...
We both know that I'm...
不太受歡迎
not very popular
與行政部門。
with the administration.
甲：原因
M: The reason
他們發現你沒有吸引力
they find you unattractive
就是這個原因
is the very reason
我發現你很有魅力。
I find you attractive.
使命？
Mission?
M：郵政局長行動。
M: Operation Postmaster.
壓制德國潛艇
To neutralize the German U-boats
在北大西洋。
in the North Atlantic.
（嘎嘎作響）
(RATTLING)
- 那麼，呃，計劃是什麼？
- And, uh, what's the plan?
-（嘆氣）
- (SIGHS)
弗萊明：U型潛艇需要
FLEMING: The U-boats need
- 燃料和魚雷。
- fuel and torpedoes.
- 哦。
- Oh.
但他們也需要
But they also need
二氧化碳過濾器
carbon dioxide filters
用於氧氣。
for oxygen.
沒有他們，他們就無法潛水
Without them, they can't dive
他們不能打獵。
and they can't hunt.
粘在表面，
Stuck on the surface,
它們已經過時了。
they're obsolete.
目標？
Target?
奧斯塔公爵夫人。
The Duchessa d'Aosta.
她是一艘意大利船
She's an Italian ship
德國人一直在使用...
the Germans have been using...
（繼續拖著椅子）
(CONTINUES DRAGGING CHAIR)
（弗萊明清嗓子）
(FLEMING CLEARS THROAT)
...加油，
...to refuel,
重新武裝並補充
re-arm and replenish
二氧化碳過濾器
the CO2 filters
對於整個艦隊。
for the entire fleet.
她隱藏了
She's hidden
西非海岸附近。
off the coast of West Africa.
一個小島
A small island
名叫費爾南多·波。
called Fernando Po.
我們希望你，嗯，擊沉她。
We want you to, um, sink her.
M：你會假扮成漁民
M: You'll be posing as fishermen
沿著西海岸航行
sailing down the west coast
在拖網漁船上
on board a trawler
裝有足夠的炸藥
loaded with enough explosives
摧毀公爵夫人。
to destroy the Duchessa.
這是特工
This is Agents
海倫和斯圖爾特。
Heron and Stewart.
他們將會工作
They'll be working
島上的臥底。
undercover on the island.
海倫先生的
Mr. Heron's
那裡已經設立了，
already established there,
經營各種業務。
running various businesses.
哪些業務？
What businesses?
賭場酒吧，
A casino bar,
和非法出口遊戲。
and illegal exports game.
有利可圖？
Profitable?
- 我做得很好。
- I do quite well.
-（輕擊聲）
- (LIGHTER CLICKS)
納粹高層
High-ranking Nazis
是我最尊貴的客戶。
are my most valued clients.
對你有好處。
Good for you.
（輕擊聲）
(LIGHTER CLICKS)
男：斯圖爾特小姐，
M: Miss Stewart,
演員和歌手，
an actress and singer,
一直在和我們一起訓練
has been training with us
過去兩年。
for the last two years.
她會擺出姿勢
She'll be posing
作為一名來自紐約的黃金交易員。
as a gold trader from New York.
她的使命是
Her mission is
引誘和分散注意力
to seduce and distract
島上的指揮
the island's Commanding
海因裡希·魯爾警官。
Officer Heinrich Luhr.
她非常有能力
She's very capable
並且有些動力。
and somewhat motivated.
先生，怎麼激勵？
Motivated how, sir?
我媽媽的身邊
My mother's side
是德國猶太人。
were German Jews.
他們是最先走的。
They were the first to go.
聽到這個消息我感到非常遺憾。
Very sorry to hear that.
我相信你會康復的。
I'm sure you'll recover.
男：我們還有44天
M: We have 44 days
在納粹之前
before the Nazis
移動他們的操作。
move their operation.
我們不會再找到他們了。
We won't find them again.
如果我要做這件事
If I'm to do this,
我需要我自己的團隊。
I'll need my own team.
你不會喜歡他們的。
You won't like them.
他們都是，呃…
They're all, uh...
瘋狂的。
mad.
他們需要這樣。
They'll need to be.
請告訴我們他們的名字。
Give us their names.
亨利·海斯。
Henry Hayes.
一個聰明的年輕愛爾蘭人
A smart, young Irishman
誰討厭納粹
who hates the Nazis
因為他的哥哥，
because his older brother,
他是我的密友，
who was a close friend of mine,
在潛艇追擊後溺水身亡
drowned after a U-boat
擊沉了他的拖網漁船。
sank his fishing trawler.
我把他置於我的羽翼之下
I've taken him under my wing
從那時起。
ever since.
他狡猾、安靜、狡猾。
He's cunning, quiet and wily.
更重要的是，
More to the point,
海耶斯是一位出色的水手
Hayes is a magnificent sailor
我相信他。
and I trust him.
如果我們要去的話
If we're going
試圖擊沉一艘大船
to try and sink a large ship,
我們需要
we'll need
「嗡嗡聲」弗雷迪蛙人。
Freddy "The Buzz" frogman.
他可以游過海峽
He can swim across the channel
他的腳被綁在一起。
with his feet tied together.
誠然，
Admittedly,
他是一名被定罪的縱火犯
he's a convicted arsonist
和可怕的痛苦
and a terrible misery
除非他正在毀掉什麼東西。
unless he's destroying something.
但他很好
But he's very good
炸毀東西。
at blowing things up.
接下來，我們需要
Next, we'll need
丹麥錘子。
the Danish hammer.
安德斯·拉森。
Anders Lassen.
長大的摔跤熊
Grew up wrestling bears
和狩獵麋鹿
and hunting elk
在他的家族莊園裡。
on his family estate.
他是一個傳奇
He's a legend
用鮑伊刀
with a Bowie knife
還有弓和箭。
and a bow and arrow.
他18歲時就逃跑了
He ran away at 18
對抗納粹
to fight the Nazis
在蓋世太保遭受酷刑之後
after the Gestapo tortured
他的兄弟死了。
his brother to death.
他放棄了切片遊戲
He gave up filleting game
為了消滅納粹。
for gutting Nazis.
然後他出現在我們的海岸上
He then turned up on our shores
準備好與我們並肩作戰。
ready to fight alongside us.
他是一隻無法控制的瘋狗
He is an uncontrollable mad dog
誰知道
who knows
一百種創意方法
a hundred creative ways
去殺一個人。
to kill a man.
最後，
And finally,
最重要的是，
and most importantly,
我們需要傑弗裡·阿普爾亞德。
we'll need Geoffrey Appleyard.
是的，我們認為你可能會。
Yes, we thought you might.
這就是為什麼我們派他來
That's why we sent him
執行偵察任務
on a reconnaissance mission
費爾南多·波。
to Fernando Po.
很遺憾，
Unfortunately,
納粹抓住了他
the Nazis nabbed him
在他回來時。
on his return.
更何況還有理由。
All the more reason.
他知道我們需要知道什麼。
He knows what we need to know.
他是一位總體規劃師
He's a master planner,
一位倖存者大師，
a master survivor,
國際象棋大師
a chess grand master
和一個拿著刀片的外科醫生。
and a surgeon with the blade.
我們一起度過了兩周
We spent two weeks together
在敦刻爾克散兵坑裡
in a Dunkirk foxhole
如果不是蘋果，
and if it wasn't for Apple,
今天我仍然會在那裡。
I would still be there today.
沒有蘋果，就沒有使命。
No Apple, no mission.
恐怕這是不可能的。
I'm afraid that's impossible.
為什麼？
Why?
M：因為他被拘留了
M: Because he's being held
整個德國駐軍
by an entire German garrison
在拉帕爾馬島。
on La Palma.
（生氣，笑）
(HUFFS, LAUGHS)
拉帕爾馬正在路上。
La Palma's on the way.
（瑪喬麗·嘲笑）
(MARJORIE SCOFFS)
- 這太瘋狂了。
- That's insanity.
- 你讓我擔心這個。
- You let me worry about that.
我必須得到我
I must get me
其中一件外套。
one of those coats.
（有趣的西方音樂演奏）
(AMUSING WESTERN MUSIC PLAYING)
（笑）
(LAUGHING)
現在，只要有機會你可以告訴我們
Now, any chance you can tell us
我們在這裡做什麼，先生？
what we're doing here, sir?
擦乾身子吧，蛙人，
Dry yourself off, frogman,
我會告訴你。
and I'll tell you.
好奇心是
The curiosity is
把我們都吃掉了，先生。
eating us all up, sir.
GUS：我道歉
GUS: I apologize
為了所有的秘密，夥計們。
for all the secrecy, chaps.
但這是
But this is
未經批准的、非官方的
an unsanctioned, unofficial
和未經授權的任務。
and unauthorized mission.
如果我們被英國人抓住
If we're picked up by the Brits,
我們都會進監獄。
we will all go to jail.
如果我們被接走
If we're picked up
由德國人，
by the Germans,
酷刑和死亡。
torture and death.
所以，這只是
So, it's just
那麼我們四個人呢？
the four of us then?
還有阿普爾亞德船長。
And Captain Appleyard.
他有責任
He's responsible
為了保護這些信息。
for securing this information.
然而他卻是
He is, however,
在一個麻煩的地方。
in a spot of bother.
他被關押
He is being held
德國人在拉帕爾馬島上。
by the Germans on La Palma.
我們的第一份工作
Our first job
就是要解放他。
is to liberate him.
- 哦，所以，就這些了，是嗎？
- Oh, so, that's all, is it?
- 格斯：沒有。
- GUS: No.
我們需要確認
We need to confirm
阿普爾亞德的智慧。
Appleyard's intelligence.
這就是為什麼
That's why
還有兩個代理
there are two more agents
前往費爾南多波的路上
on their way to Fernando Po
正如我們所說，乘火車。
by train, as we speak.
到底在做什麼？
Doing what, exactly?
他們將確保
They'll be ensuring
那些船
that those ships
都裝滿了物資，
are filled with supplies,
所以它們值得炸毀
so they're worth blowing up
首先。
in the first place.
（火車喇叭鳴響）
(TRAIN HORN BLARING)
瑪喬麗：這是一回事
MARJORIE: It's one thing
接管世界，
taking over the world,
但他們必須這樣做嗎
but do they have to
也接管廚房？
take over the kitchen too?
都是香腸啊
It's all sausage,
捲心菜和黑麵包。
cabbage and black bread.
海倫：誰會
HERON: Who would
你有首選嗎？
you have preferred?
MARJORIE：法國的提議
MARJORIE: The French offer
精緻的古典風格。
the refined classical take.
牛坡，
Cote de boeuf,
奶酪、le beurre...
fromage, le beurre...
- 夠了！
- ca suffit!
- （男人說話含糊不清）
- (MEN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
田園風又怎樣呢
What about the rustic
意大利人的自發性？
spontaneity of the Italians?
他們的油、扁麵條、
Their oils, the linguine,
西紅柿。
the tomatoes.
我會爬過扁麵條
I'd climb over the linguine
去吃寬麵條。
to get to the fettucine.
但辛吉亞萊。
But the cinghiale.
瑪喬麗：嗯。
MARJORIE: Mmm.
你讓我和野豬在一起。
You have me with the wild boar.
但話又說回來，
But then again,
西班牙報價
the Spanish offer
自助餐
the smorgasbord
地區海鮮飯
of the regional paella
和小吃。
and tapas.
還有安達盧西亞伊比利亞火腿。
And Jamon Iberico Andalucia.
所以？
So?
我們之間
We're between
岩石和堅硬的地方。
a rock and a hard place.
如果英國人贏得戰爭
If the Brits win the war,
我們被炸魚和薯條困住了。
we're stuck with fish and chips.
如果德國人贏得戰爭
If the Germans win the war,
我們被這個菜單困住了。
we're stuck with this menu.
所以？
So?
我們要香腸，
We'll have the sausage,
捲心菜
the cabbage
-還有黑麵包。
- and the black bread please.
-（嘆氣）
- (SIGHS)
非常好。謝謝。
Tres bien. Merci.
（士兵們笑，
(SOLDIERS LAUGHING,
說話含糊不清）
SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
（呼氣）
(EXHALES)
我們的情況？
Our situation?
穩定的。
Steady.
（含糊不清的對話）
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
（激動人心的音樂演奏）
(EXCITING MUSIC PLAYING)
穩定的。
Steady.
（呼氣）
(EXHALES)
現在。
Now.
（士兵們講德語
(SOLDIERS SPEAKING GERMAN
含糊其辭，笑）
INDISTINCTLY, LAUGHING)
（在德國）
(IN GERMAN)
瑪喬麗：嗯。
MARJORIE: Mmm.
（英語）我累壞了。
(IN ENGLISH) I'm exhausted.
（在德國）
(IN GERMAN)
-（笑聲停止）
- (LAUGHING STOPS)
-（音樂漸弱）
- (MUSIC FADES)
-（輕笑）
- (CHUCKLES)
-（士兵們噓聲）
- (SOLDIERS SHUSHING)
（吞嚥）
(GULPS)
Entschuldigung，bitte。
Entschuldigung, bitte.
（激動人心的音樂演奏）
(EXCITING MUSIC PLAYING)
（士兵們含糊其辭）
(SOLDIERS SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
警官：（用英語）停下來！
OFFICER: (IN ENGLISH) Halt!
（懸疑的音樂播放）
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
（閒聊停止）
(CHATTER STOPS)
（在德國）
(IN GERMAN)
（英語）有問題嗎？
(IN ENGLISH) Is there a problem?
（在德國）
(IN GERMAN)
（英語）我可以應付
(IN ENGLISH) I can manage
我自己，謝謝。
myself, thank you.
（在德國）
(IN GERMAN)
（用英語講）
(IN ENGLISH)
請允許我，斯圖爾特小姐。
Allow me, Miss Stewart.
（音樂漸弱）
(MUSIC FADES)
（在德國）
(IN GERMAN)
（英語）請允許我。
(IN ENGLISH) Allow me.
謝謝。
Thank you.
（激動人心的音樂演奏）
(EXCITING MUSIC PLAYING)
士兵：普羅斯特！
SOLDIER: Prost!
（士兵們含糊其辭）
(SOLDIERS SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
（激動人心的音樂繼續）
(EXCITING MUSIC CONTINUES)
海倫：門。
HERON: Door.
鎖定。
Locked.
海倫：案子？
HERON: Case?
正在努力。
Working on it.
（解鎖箱子）
(UNLOCKS CASE)
（士兵們含糊其辭）
(SOLDIERS SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
（撥號盤點擊）
(DIAL CLICKING)
（電話鈴聲）
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
（信號蜂鳴聲）
(SIGNAL BEEPING)
接線員：先生，請聯繫。
OPERATOR: Sir, contact.
-（信號蜂鳴聲）
- (SIGNAL BEEPING)
- 接觸。
- Contact.
站在。
Standing by.
瑪喬麗：
MARJORIE:
公爵夫人的清單。準備好？
Duchessa's manifest. Ready?
- 準備好。
- Ready.
- 400枚B級魚雷。查看。
- 400 B-grade torpedoes. Check.
（激動人心的音樂演奏）
(EXCITING MUSIC PLAYING)
（信號蜂鳴聲）
(SIGNAL BEEPING)
操作員：400 枚 B 級魚雷。
OPERATOR: 400 B-grade torpedoes.
男：檢查一下。
M: Check.
查看。
Check.
瑪喬麗：
MARJORIE:
柴油5000噸。查看。
5,000 tons of diesel. Check.
（點擊）
(CLICKING)
（信號蜂鳴聲）
(SIGNAL BEEPING)
運營商：5000噸柴油。
OPERATOR: 5,000 tons of diesel.
- 中尉。
- Lieutenant.
- 接線員：是嗎，先生？
- OPERATOR: Yes, sir?
男：檢查一下。
M: Check.
-（信號蜂鳴聲）
- (SIGNAL BEEPING)
- HERON：檢查。
- HERON: Check.
10,000 個二氧化碳過濾器。
10,000 carbon dioxide filters.
查看。
Check.
（士兵們含糊其辭）
(SOLDIERS SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
鸛鳥的消息結束了，先生。
End of message from Stork, sir.
確認收據。
Confirm receipt.
（信號蜂鳴聲）
(SIGNAL BEEPING)
HERON：收據已確認。
HERON: Receipt confirmed.
緊急，支票。
Urgent, Chequers.
準備好車。
Get the car ready.
通知弗萊明。
Inform Fleming.
我們把它打包吧。
Let's pack it up.
搶銀行沒有意義
No point robbing the bank
如果金庫裡沒有黃金。
if there's no gold in the vault.
（激動人心的音樂繼續）
(EXCITING MUSIC CONTINUES)
（士兵們交談，大笑）
(SOLDIERS CONVERSING, LAUGHING)
謝謝。
Thank you.
知道這真是令人欣慰
It's truly comforting to know
至少有一位紳士
there's at least one gentleman
在世界上。
in the world.
士兵：啊！ （德語）
SOLDIER: Ah! (SPEAKING GERMAN)
笨蛋！
Idiot!
（蒼鷺，德語）
(HERON, IN GERMAN)
（英語）美好的一天。
(IN ENGLISH) Good day.
（音樂漸弱）
(MUSIC FADES)
香腸、捲心菜
Sausage, cabbage
和黑麵包。
and black bread.
（嘆氣）
(SIGHS)
男：希特勒
MAN: Hitler
已向我們發出報價。
has made us an offer.
綏靖政策。
An appeasement.
但我們必須撤軍，
But we must step down our army,
投降我們的海軍
surrender our Navy
並接受納粹統治。
and accept Nazi rule.
否則，他保證
Otherwise, he promises
英國的徹底毀滅
total destruction of Britain
和她的帝國。
and her empire.
我們最好的選擇
Our best option
就是接受希特勒的交易
is to take Hitler's deal
當我們可以的時候。
while we can.
空軍元帥對此表示同意。
The Air Marshal agrees.
他還有更多的炸彈
He has more bombs,
更多的人，更多的機器。
more men, more machines.
我們活不了多久了。
We won't survive much longer.
你必須做
You have to make
你能做出的唯一決定
the only decision you can make
憑良心來說，
in good conscience,
總理。
Prime Minister.
丘吉爾：天哪，姑娘們。
CHURCHILL: Good God, girls.
聽聽你自己的聲音。
Listen to yourselves.
這不是綏靖政策，
It's not appeasement,
這是投降。
it's surrender.
你還是沒有意識到
You still fail to realize
我們的對手是誰。
who we're up against.
尊敬的總理，
With respect, Prime Minister,
是你沒有意識到。
it's you who doesn't realize.
我們不能指望打敗他。
We cannot hope to defeat him.
希特勒是
Hitler is
罪惡的主要源泉，
the mainspring of evil,
陰溝鳥。
a guttersnipe.
這不是一個男人
This is not a man
我們可以與之談判。
that we can negotiate with.
我讀過他的書
I've read his book,
龐德海軍上將。
Admiral Pound.
男人是個惡毒的人，
The man is a vicious,
受害的意識形態。
victimized ideologue.
他不值得信任。
He cannot be trusted.
如果我這麼想的話
If I thought that
我們本可以實現和平
we could've achieved peace
通過投降，
through surrendering,
我早就這麼做了。
I'd have done it already.
我們需要阻止我們的國家
We need to stop our country
免於飢餓。
from starving.
我們需要
We need
300萬噸物資
three million tons of supplies
橫渡大西洋
to cross the Atlantic
每個月。
every month.
我們目前正在失去
We are currently losing
其中 50% 是 U 艇攻擊。
50% of that to U-boat attacks.
接受這筆交易的另一個原因。
Another reason to take the deal.
我還沒說完，
I've not finished,
阿爾吉儂，親愛的。
Algernon, darling.
我們需要美國人
We need the Americans,
他們會的
and they will
永遠不要參戰
never enter the war
如果我們已經出現
if we already appear
成為失敗的一方。
to be a losing side.
結束與德國的敵對行動
Ending hostilities with Germany
是最好的路徑
is the best path
擺脫這個混亂。
out of this mess.
我們都一致同意，
We are all in agreement,
總理。
Prime Minister.
謝謝你們，先生們。
Thank you, gentlemen.
（嚴肅地）是的，
(STERNLY) Yes,
謝謝你們，先生們！
thank you, gentlemen!
（懸疑的音樂播放）
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
（門打開）
(DOOR OPENS)
丘吉爾：弗萊明先生，
CHURCHILL: M, Fleming,
這最好是個好消息。
this better be good news.
M：總理，
M: Prime Minister,
我們這裡有清單，先生。
we have the manifest here, sir.
已確認
It's been confirmed
公爵夫人
the Duchessa
裝滿了物資
is fully laden with supplies
保留U型潛艇
to keep the U-boats
無限期運行。
operational indefinitely.
如果我們要把她沉沒
If we're going to sink her,
現在是時候了。
now is the time.
他們正在路上。
They're on their way.
他們的機會呢？
And their chances?
好吧，如果有人可以，他們就可以。
Well, if anyone can, they can.
但如果我們被發現了
But if we're discovered,
議會將罷免你
parliament will remove you
從辦公室。
from office.
出色地，
Well,
我們最好確保
we'd better make sure
那時我們就沒有被發現。
we're not discovered then.
（懸疑的音樂漸漸消失）
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC FADES)
我們會接受它
We'll take it
從懸崖邊。
from the cliffside.
這是 85 英尺的陡坡。
It's an 85-foot sheer climb.
沒有人應該注意到
No one should notice
一個小的、無害的
a small, innocuous
漁船。
fishing vessel.
我們將在樹林裡安營紮寨
We'll set up in the woods
看看我們面臨著什麼，
and see what we're up against,
然後我們就去夜襲。
then we'll go for a night raid.
悄悄溜進去，
Slip in quietly,
找到蘋果，快點出來。
find Apple, come out fast.
數字？
Numbers?
情報表明
Intelligence suggests
駐軍50至60人。
a garrison of 50 to 60.
每個應該是15個左右。
That should be about 15 each.
拉森，盡量不要貪心。
Lassen, try not to be greedy.
你確實有名氣。
You do have a reputation.
我殺戮的日子結束了。
My killing days are over.
我就在這裡
I'm just here
作為維和觀察員。
as a peacekeeping observer.
（男人輕笑）
(MEN CHUCKLE)
弗雷迪，把工具包裝進袋子裡，
Freddy, bag the kit,
讓武器安靜下來。
silence the weapons.
（激動人心的音樂演奏）
(EXCITING MUSIC PLAYING)
（海鷗的叫聲）
(SEAGULL SQUAWKING)
（槍旋塞）
(GUN COCKS)
（戲劇性的音樂演奏）
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
（士兵們用德語喊叫）
(SOLDIERS SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
弗雷迪：我們什麼時候走？
FREDDY: When do we go?
格斯：0200。
GUS: 0200.
先拿塔樓，
Take the towers first,
然後進入廣播室，
then move onto the radio room,
軍營並結束
barracks and end up
在控制室...
in the control room...
-（遠處有狗叫）
- (DOG BARKS IN THE DISTANCE)
- 我們有什麼在這裡？
- What do we have here?
蓋世太保。
Gestapo.
你怎麼知道的？
How'd you know?
GUS：他們越糟糕，
GUS: The badder they are,
他們穿得越好。
the better they're dressed.
我真的必須得到我
I really must get me
其中一件外套。
one of those coats.
他們肯定是為了蘋果而來。
They must be here for Apple.
要麼就是折磨
It's either torture
或者，呃，提取，先生。
or, uh, extraction, sir.
GUS：如果他們把他救出來
GUS: If they extract him,
這將是蘋果的終結。
it'll be the end of Apple.
我們不會再見到他了。
We won't be seeing him again.
恐怕先生們，
I'm afraid, gentlemen,
我們不會去
we're not going
享受奢華的夜晚。
to have the luxury of night.
本來打算
We're going
現在必須進去。
to have to go in now.
（士兵們講德語）
(SOLDIERS SPEAKING GERMAN)
（兩人都用德語喊叫）
(BOTH SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
-（箭矢呼嘯）
- (ARROWS WHIZZING)
-（士兵咕嚕聲）
- (SOLDIERS GRUNT)
（喋喋不休）
(SPLUTTERS)
（音樂漸弱）
(MUSIC FADES)
（英語）所以，
(IN ENGLISH) So,
那兒發生了什麼事？
what's happened there then?
看起來像
It looks like
他們已經被堵住了
they've been plugged
充滿了箭，海西。
full of arrows, Haysey.
那麼，箭頭去哪兒了呢？
Well, where did the arrows go?
弗雷迪：直接穿過他們。
FREDDY: Straight through them.
（拉森咕嚕聲）
(LASSEN GRUNTING)
有
There were
另一邊還有兩個。
two more round the other side.
他們現在在哪裡？
Where are they now?
和這兩個是同一個地方。
Same place as these two.
納粹天堂。
Nazi heaven.
好吧，我們有
Well, we've got
不到七分鐘
less than seven minutes
在他們被錯過之前。
before they're missed.
警報，狗。沒有一個是好的。
Alarms, dogs. None of it good.
（槍聲響起）
(GUNS FIRING)
深入瞭解發動機。
Go undercover of the engine.
只能打破蓋子
Only break cover
當事情發生的時候。
when things go bang.
（嘆氣）
(SIGHS)
我有一個好主意，拉森。
I have a great idea, Lassen.
你為何不出發
Why don't you march off
自己
by yourself
並填補那些德國人
and fill those Germans
充滿了箭頭？
full of arrows?
（緊張的西方音樂演奏）
(TENSE WESTERN MUSIC PLAYING)
（咕嚕聲）
(GRUNTS)
GUS：弗雷迪，拿起剪刀
GUS: Freddy, grab the scissors
並幫助他修好柵欄。
and help him with that fence.
好的，先生。
Aye, sir.
（激動人心的音樂演奏）
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
（咕嚕聲）
(GRUNTS)
（士兵含糊其辭）
(SOLDIER SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
（車輛發動機嗡嗡作響）
(VEHICLE ENGINE WHIRRING)
海西，你和我在一起。
Haysey, you're with me.
我們向左走。
We go left.
弗雷迪、拉森，你們往右走。
Freddy, Lassen, you go right.
先生們，裝滿你的靴子，
Fill your boots, gentlemen,
祝你胃口好。
and bon appetit.
（截圖）
(SNIPPING)
（發動機濺射）
(ENGINE SPUTTERING)
- 塔樓見。
- See you at the tower.
-（槍旋塞）
- (GUNS COCK)
GUS：請記住，先生們，
GUS: And remember, gentlemen,
嘗試玩得開心。
try to have fun.
-（槍聲安靜）
- (GUNS FIRING QUIETLY)
-（士兵們大聲叫喊）
- (SOLDIERS CLAMORING)
（發動機呼呼）
(ENGINE WHIRRING)
（軍官講德語）
(OFFICER SPEAKING GERMAN)
（男子在廣播中講話）
(MAN SPEAKING ON RADIO)
（槍聲安靜）
(GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
（發動機呼呼）
(ENGINE WHIRRING)
（槍聲安靜）
(GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
-（呻吟聲）
- (GROANS)
-（英語）到目前為止，一切都很好。
- (IN ENGLISH) So far, so good.
-（發動機呼呼聲）
- (ENGINE WHIRRING)
- 做得相當好，海西。
- Doing rather well, Haysey.
噢，為什麼要謝謝你，先生。
Oh, why thank you, sir.
（士兵說德語）
(SOLDIER SPEAKING GERMAN)
（軍官講德語）
(OFFICER SPEAKING GERMAN)
（2 號官員說德語）
(OFFICER 2 SPEAKING GERMAN)
（士兵們笑）
(SOLDIERS LAUGHING)
（格斯哈哈大笑）
(GUS LAUGHING UPROARIOUSLY)
（停止笑）
(STOPS LAUGHING)
（英語）非常好。
(IN ENGLISH) It's very good.
-（槍聲安靜）
- (GUNS FIRING QUIETLY)
-（士兵們尖叫）
- (SOLDIERS SCREAMING)
（槍聲安靜）
(GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
（1 號官員說德語）
(OFFICER 1 SPEAKING GERMAN)
（2 號官員說德語）
(OFFICER 2 SPEAKING GERMAN)
（1 號官員說德語）
(OFFICER 1 SPEAKING GERMAN)
（德語）
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
- （警官 3 說德語）
- (OFFICER 3 SPEAKING GERMAN)
-（音樂漸強、漸弱）
- (MUSIC CRESCENDOES, FADES)
-（爆炸）
- (EXPLOSION)
-（士兵們尖叫）
- (SOLDIERS SCREAMING)
（所有人都在叫嚷）
(ALL CLAMORING)
（英語）聽起來像
(IN ENGLISH) Sounds like
隱身模式結束了
stealth mode's over.
海西，下來！
Haysey, down!
（士兵們尖叫）
(SOLDIERS SCREAMING)
（子彈叮噹作響）
(BULLETS CLANGING)
（機槍停）
(MACHINE GUN STOPS)
（警報聲響起）
(ALARM BLARING)
（士兵們在外面喊叫）
(SOLDIERS CLAMORING OUTSIDE)
（樂觀
(UPBEAT
電子音樂演奏）
ELECTRONIC MUSIC PLAYING)
-（槍聲安靜）
- (GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
-（呻吟聲）
- (GROANS)
（咳嗽）
(COUGHING)
-（黑客）
- (HACKS)
-（槍聲安靜）
- (GUN FIRES QUIETLY)
（士兵咳嗽）
(SOLDIERS COUGHING)
（士兵們喊叫、呻吟）
(SOLDIERS SHOUT, GROAN)
（士兵呻吟聲）
(SOLDIER GROANS)
（槍聲安靜）
(GUN FIRES QUIETLY)
-（士兵呻吟）
- (SOLDIER GROANING)
-（槍聲安靜）
- (GUN FIRES QUIETLY)
（用德語喊叫）
(SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
-（槍聲安靜）
- (GUN FIRES QUIETLY)
-（呻吟聲）
- (GROANS)
（兩人都咕噥著）
(BOTH GRUNTING)
（士兵們大聲叫喊）
(SOLDIERS CLAMORING)
（呻吟聲）
(GROANS)
- 不！不！（呻吟聲）
- Nein! Nein! (GROANS)
-（咕嚕聲）
- (GRUNTS)
（嗚咽聲）
(WHIMPERS)
（兩人咕嚕聲）
(BOTH GRUNT)
（吵鬧、尖叫）
(CLAMORING, SCREAMING)
（兩人都咕噥著）
(BOTH GRUNTING)
-（刺傷）
- (STABBING)
-（軍官呻吟）
- (OFFICER GROANS)
-（拉森咕噥）
- (LASSEN GRUNTS)
-（士兵大喊）
- (SOLDIER YELLS)
（大喊）
(YELLING)
（拉森和士兵咕嚕聲）
(LASSEN AND SOLDIER GRUNT)
-（士兵用德語喊叫）
- (SOLDIER SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
-（槍聲安靜）
- (GUN FIRES QUIETLY)
（音樂漸弱）
(MUSIC FADES)
（拉森氣喘吁吁）
(LASSEN PANTING)
（用英語講）
(IN ENGLISH)
我們彼此認識嗎？
Do we know each other?
- 不。
- No.
-（士兵窒息）
- (SOLDIER CHOKING)
（濺射聲）
(SPLUTTERING)
（刀子叮噹響）
(KNIFE CLINKS)
- (STAB)
- (STABS)
-（士兵尖叫聲）
- (SOLDIER SCREAMS)
（清嗓子）
(CLEARS THROAT)
（拉森咕噥）
(LASSEN GRUNTS)
那是一顆心嗎，拉森？
Is that a heart, Lassen?
為避免疑義。
For the avoidance of doubt.
蘋果，老男孩。
Apple, old boy.
- 格斯。
- Gus.
- GUS：我看你們兩個已經見過面了。
- GUS: I see you two have met.
這是海西。
This is Haysey.
- 傑弗裡：很高興，海西。
- GEOFFREY: Pleasure, Haysey.
- 快樂是我的。
- Pleasure's mine.
我想你可能需要這些。
I thought you might need these.
真高興為你著想。
Jolly thoughtful of you.
弗雷迪：你們都找到他了嗎？
FREDDY: You all find him?
哦，好極了。
Oh, goody.
該死的地獄，
Bloody hell,
你的乳頭怎麼了？
what happened to your nipples?
你沒事吧？
You all right?
無法拔掉我的電源，可以嗎？
Couldn't unplug me, could you?
電池還開著。
Battery's still on.
（電劈啪作響）
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
（有趣的
(INTRIGUING
西洋音樂演奏）
WESTERN MUSIC PLAYING)
（格斯笑）
(GUS LAUGHING)
（戲劇性的吉他音樂演奏）
(DRAMATIC GUITAR MUSIC PLAYING)
（電機呼呼）
(MOTOR WHIRRING)
（眾人含糊其辭）
(CROWD SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
（意大利語問候）
(GREETING IN ITALIAN)
（模糊不清的喋喋不休）
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
（士兵咕嚕聲）
(SOLDIERS GRUNT)
（霧號聲）
(FOGHORN BLARES)
（用英語講）
(IN ENGLISH)
你看到公爵夫人了嗎
Did you see the Duchessa,
拖船？
the tug boats?
相反
And rather
很多納粹士兵。
a lot of Nazi soldiers.
為什麼你的報告中沒有這一點？
Why wasn't that in your report?
因為那些士兵
Because those soldiers
還有那些槍，
and those guns,
那些 S-Boats 都是新的。
and those S-Boats are all new.
還有很多
That's a lot more
比男孩們期待的還要多。
than the boys are expecting.
一個月前，
A month ago,
有十幾個機械師。
it was a dozen mechanics.
六個醉酒的水手。
Six drunk sailors.
兩個胖西班牙人。
Two fat Spaniards.
還有梨樹上的納粹。
And a Nazi in a pear tree.
我會說，
I'd say,
我們需要更多幫助。
we're gonna need more help.
你把這個留給我吧。
You leave that to me.
- 當然。
- Of course.
-（男人呻吟）
- (MAN GROANS)
（男子用德語大喊）
(MAN YELLING IN GERMAN)
-（咕嚕聲）
- (GRUNTS)
- HERON：但是現在……
- HERON: But right now...
-（男人呻吟）
- (MAN GROANS)
- ...你需要見見那個人。
- ...you need to meet that man.
（笑）
(LAUGHING)
（有趣的音樂播放）
(INTRIGUING MUSIC PLAYING)
海倫：你的男人。
HERON: Your man.
你來這裡的原因。
The reason you're here.
男人：啊。
MAN: Ah.
唯一的事情
The only thing
比納粹還壞……
worse than a Nazi...
是他。
is him.
（有趣的音樂繼續）
(INTRIGUING MUSIC CONTINUES)
（敲門）
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
（音樂漸弱）
(MUSIC FADES)
（門打開）
(DOOR OPENS)
（士兵，德語）
(SOLDIER, IN GERMAN)
（士兵說德語）
(SOLDIER SPEAKING GERMAN)
（用英語講）
(IN ENGLISH)
我很失望，赫倫。
I'm very disappointed, Heron.
有16個箱子
There are 16 crates
在我的倉庫裡
in my warehouse
你還沒有
you have not yet
運往大陸。
shipped to the mainland.
不用擔心，盧爾先生。
No need to fret, Herr Luhr.
他們仍然會被交付
They'll still be delivered
在約定的日期之前。
by the agreed date.
那可能。
That may be.
但它們佔用了寶貴的空間。
But they take up valuable space.
為此，我期望
For this, I expect
顯著減少
a significant reduction
在你的費用中。
in your fee.
- HERON：我可以做到 5%...
- HERON: I can do 5%...
-（嘲笑）
- (SCOFFS)
……作為一種善意的姿態。
...as a gesture of goodwill.
二十。並且不要浪費
Twenty. And don't waste
我討價還價的寶貴時間。
my precious time haggling.
瑪喬麗：嗯，
MARJORIE: Well,
嚴格來講，
strictly speaking,
不應有任何減少，
there should be no reductions,
因為還沒有
since there's not yet been
任何違反合同的行為。
any breach of contract.
五不止於禮貌，
Five is more than polite,
20響就像一個酸味的音符，
20 rings like a sour note,
它很吵。
it jars.
它罐子嗎？
It jars?
我是不是
Am I being
被指責不和諧？
accused of disharmony?
我認為
I take that
作為個人侮辱。
as a personal affront.
我假設
And I am supposing
你不是秘書。
you are not the secretary.
斯圖爾特小姐是聯繫人
Miss Stewart is the contact
我說我會安排。
I said I'd arrange.
啊，你的紐約黃金聯繫人嗎？
Ah, your New York gold contact?
我告訴你了，
I told you,
我已經有了
I already have
令人滿意的安排。
a satisfying arrangement.
請坐。
Have a seat.
謝謝。
Thank you.
（海因裡希說德語）
(HEINRICH SPEAKING GERMAN)
（英語）嗯，
(IN ENGLISH) Well,
我希望我不會失望。
I hope I don't disappoint.
（笑）
(LAUGHS)
我無法做出決定
I can't make a decision
在本次演講中。
on this presentation.
早些年。
Early days.
好吧，如果早點
Well, if early days
來得太早了，
do come too soon,
和季節的變化
and seasons change
與獵人的月亮。
with a Hunter's Moon.
（在德國）
(IN GERMAN)
唔。
Hmm.
（用英語講）
(IN ENGLISH)
我不得不說，海倫，
I have to say, Heron,
對於你所有的缺點，
for all your flaws,
你確實有一個習慣
you do have a habit
從帽子里拉兔子。
of pulling rabbits from hats.
（古典音樂演奏）
(CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING)
那麼，需要多少黃金
So, how much gold
你想搬家嗎
do you wish to move,
- 斯圖爾特小姐？
- Miss Stewart?
-（輕擊聲）
- (LIGHTER CLICKS)
能找到多少就找多少。
As much as you can find.
正如我之前提到的，
As I mentioned before,
我已經有了
I do already have
一個非常有利可圖的安排。
a very profitable arrangement.
儘管有你的評論，
And despite of your commentary,
我為自己感到驕傲
I pride myself
關於維護和諧。
on maintaining harmony.
現在，我為什麼要招待你？
Now, why should I entertain you?
因為你會賺更多的錢
Because you'll make more money
並有很多樂趣
and have lots of fun
這樣做的同時。
whilst doing so.
如果我不遵守諾言，
If I'm not good for my word,
別付錢給我。
don't pay me.
（在德國）
(IN GERMAN)
（笑）
(LAUGHS)
（英語）太棒了。
(IN ENGLISH) Bravo.
我會和我的人民交談
I will talk to my people
然後我們會合。
and then we'll rendezvous.
迷人的。
Lovely.
當狡猾的紅貓
When the sly red cat
黎明時吠叫，
barks at dawn,
並為了自己的快樂而殺人，
and kills just for her pleasure,
誰分享這頓飯
who shares the meal
貓確實偷了
the cat did steal
當兩人都高興地看著的時候？
when both looked on in pleasure?
Auf wiedersehen。
Auf wiedersehen.
（在德國）
(IN GERMAN)
（笑聲）
(CHUCKLES)
（古典音樂
(CLASSICAL MUSIC
繼續播放）
CONTINUES PLAYING)
（古典音樂漸弱）
(CLASSICAL MUSIC FADES)
（緊張的音樂播放）
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
（嘆氣）
(SIGHS)
（人們說話含糊不清）
(PEOPLE SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
（打火機閃爍）
(FLICKING LIGHTER)
這個謎語是一個很好的接觸。
The riddle was a nice touch.
（嘆氣）
(SIGHS)
鉤子進來了
The hook's in.
（繼續閃爍打火機）
(CONTINUES FLICKING LIGHTER)
現在要小心
Now be careful
你如何把他捲入。
how you reel him in.
（吸氣）
(INHALES)
我會確定
I'll make sure
港口空了
the harbor's empty
當男孩們到達時。
when the boys arrive.
你打算怎麼做？
How are you going to do that?
我會在我的俱樂部舉辦一個聚會。
I'll throw a party at my club.
為軍官舉辦的化裝舞會
A costume party for the officers
和碼頭的第二次聚會
and a second party at the dock
對於士兵來說。
for the soldiers.
人們喜歡我的聚會。
People like my parties.
除了盧爾之外的所有人。
Everyone but Luhr.
那將是你的工作。
That will be your job.
所有的老鼠
All the rats
將跟隨風笛手。
will follow the piper.
傑弗裡：那麼，
GEOFFREY: So,
如果我理解正確的話
if I understand correctly,
我們目前
we're currently
在拉帕爾馬島這裡。
here in La Palma.
我們將四處航行
We'll sail around
德國控制的非洲
German-controlled Africa
費爾南多·波，
to Fernando Po,
這只是
which is just
赤道以北，
north of the Equator,
就在西非海岸附近。
just off the West African coast.
那麼這是最短路線嗎？
So that's the shortest route?
是的，但我們不
Yes, but we don't
想要更短。
want to go shorter.
我們的首要任務是不被人看到。
Our priority is not to be seen.
你的意思是，再次見到。
You mean, be seen again.
再次？變得有點馬虎
Again? Getting a little sloppy
現在就輪到我們了，Gussy？
on us now, Gussy?
已經有磨合了嗎？
Had a run-in already?
別管我們，蘋果，老男孩。
Never mind us, Apple, old boy.
再次提醒我
Remind me again
你是怎麼找到你的乳頭的
how you found your nipples
連接到汽車電池。
attached to a car battery.
（咯咯笑）
(CHUCKLING)
是的。不是我的錯。
Yes. Wasn't my fault.
智力不好。
Bad intelligence.
而且這幾乎是值得的
Plus it was almost worth it
觀看
to watch
工作中的奪心者。
the heart-snatcher at work.
我更出名的是一個情人
I'm better known as a lover
比戰士。
than a fighter.
耶穌基督！
Jesus Christ!
如果這就是你戰鬥的方式
If that's how you fight,
我不願意看到你愛。
I'd hate to see you love.
你沒有
You don't have
擔心這個，
to worry about that,
你對我來說太漂亮了。
you're too pretty for me.
另一方面，弗雷迪...
Freddy, on the other hand...
你得先抓住我。
You'd have to catch me first.
我確實喜歡打獵。
I do love to hunt.
你會很幸運。
You'd be lucky.
我真的變得很熱了。
I'm really getting quite hot.
無論如何，我的建議是
Anyway, my suggestion is
我們採取這條更廣泛的路線。
that we take this wider route.
明顯更長了
It's obviously longer
但應該避免
but it should avoid
任何尷尬的對話
any awkward conversations
與德國潛艇
with German U-boats
或英國軍艦。
or British warships.
取決於天氣，
Weather-dependent,
我們應該能到達那裡
we should make it there
15 天內。
in 15 days.
同意。
Agreed.
海西，你認為
Haysey, do you think
你能做到嗎？
you could manage that?
交給我吧，先生。
Leave it to me, sir.
（戲劇性的音樂演奏）
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
（人們笑，
(PEOPLE LAUGHING,
說話含糊不清）
SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
-（男人大喊）
- (MAN SHOUTS)
-（音樂漸弱）
- (MUSIC FADES)
照你說的去做
Just do as you're told
- 再給我一杯飲料！
- and get me another drink!
-（眼鏡叮噹聲）
- (GLASSES CLINK)
男人：船長，先生。
MAN: Captain, sir.
我可以給你弄點吃的嗎？
Can I get you something to eat?
我可以……這邊過來嗎？
May I... Come this way.
-（物體碰撞聲）
- (OBJECTS CLATTERING)
- 把你的手拿開。
- Take your hands off me.
（船長呼氣）
(CAPTAIN EXHALES)
你知道，
You know,
我喜歡你，費米。
I like you, Femi.
但你又觸碰了我
But you touch me again
你會進監獄的。
and you're going to jail.
費米。
Femi.
（閒聊繼續）
(CHATTER CONTINUES)
我來對付他。
I'll deal with him.
請保重
Please take care
斯圖爾特小姐的。
of Miss Stewart.
你知道自己需要什麼，
You know what you need,
比內亞隊長？
Captain Binea?
我知道我需要什麼。
I know what I need.
但你呢，裡卡多？
But do you, Ricardo?
你需要再喝一杯。
You need another drink.
馬蒂，
Marty,
好東西。
good stuff.
裡卡多，這就是我愛你的原因。
Ricardo, that's why I love you.
- 你明白。
- You understand.
-（玻璃叮噹聲）
- (GLASS CLINKS)
HERON：我是費爾南多·波。
HERON: This is Fernando Po.
歡迎大家。
Everybody's welcome.
Si...大家。
Si... Everybody.
我認為太多的身體。
Too many body I think.
（男人笑）
(MAN LAUGHING)
阿曼多？
Armando?
你摔倒了嗎
Have you fallen out
和我們的新朋友？
with our new friends?
（嘆氣）這不公平，裡卡多。
(SIGHS) It's not fair, Ricardo.
這是我的港灣。
This is my harbor.
我是負責人。
I am in charge.
他們踩到你的腳趾了嗎？
Are they stepping on your toes?
他們不是踩踏，而是跺腳！
They don't step, they stamp!
他們什麼也沒告訴比尼亞船長。
They tell Captain Binea nothing.
（閒聊停止）
(CHATTER STOPS)
直到現在我才聽到
Only now do I hear
公爵夫人
the Duchessa
提前離開港口。
is leaving the harbor early.
（閒聊繼續）
(CHATTER RESUMES)
好吧，擺脫了。
Well, good riddance.
港口將再次屬於你。
The harbor will be yours again.
你什麼時候有空
When will you be free
那個醜陋的容器？
of that ugly vessel?
三天前。
Three days earlier.
那麼我們應該
Then we should
再喝一杯。
have another drink.
慶祝一下。馬蒂...
To celebrate. Marty...
再來一輪
Another round
為我們的港務長。
for our Harbor Master.
那麼，船長，你知道嗎？
So, Captain, do you know
他們希望搬遷到哪裡？
where they wish to relocate?
這既不是貓也不是狗
It's neither cat nor dog
以殺人為樂，
that kills for fun,
這是潑婦，不是另一個。
it's the vixen, not another.
只有兩個
There's only two
以殺人為樂，
that kill for fun,
我漂亮的朋友，
my pretty friend,
狐貍和他的人類兄弟。
the fox and his human brother.
-（笑）
- (LAUGHING)
-（瑪喬麗輕笑）
- (MARJORIE CHUCKLES)
我相信我有
I believe I have
解決了你的小謎語。
resolved your little riddle.
起首。你打得很好。
Chapeau. You play well.
（竊聽）
(TAPPING)
說起狐貍，
Speaking of foxes,
霍洛維茨和邁耶，
Horowitz and Meyer,
西47街。
West 47th Street.
你聽說過他們嗎？
Have you heard of them?
我不相信我有，沒有。
I don't believe I have, no.
（打火機叮噹聲）
(LIGHTER CLINKS)
（喋喋不休的聲音消失）
(CHATTER FADES)
（打火機輕輕叮噹響）
(LIGHTER CLINKS SOFTLY)
他們是最大的黃金交易商
They're the largest gold traders
位於紐約市中心
in Midtown New York
你還沒有聽說過他們嗎？
and you haven't heard of them?
恐怕我沒有，沒有。
I'm afraid I haven't, no.
我當然很熟悉，
I am familiar, of course,
與霍洛維茨和海姆。
with Horowitz and Haim.
但他們在西邊
But they're in the west side
城市的。
of the city.
但話又說回來，
But then again,
我確定你已經
I'm sure you already
你知道這一點，不是嗎？
knew that, didn't you?
我很好奇，
I'm curious,
你怎麼找到
how do you find
與猶太人打交道？
dealing with the Jew?
哦親愛的。 （笑聲）
Oh, dear. (CHUCKLES)
我從一個網羅中滑落
I've slipped from one snare
卻發現自己在另一個人身上。
only to find myself in another.
我該怎麼說呢？
How shall I put this?
我害怕你傑出的領袖
I fear your brilliant leader
已被錯誤描述
has mischaracterized
古老的賈胡達部落。
the ancient tribe of Jahuda.
他們的能力不僅
Their ability to not only
生存3000年
survive 3,000 years
脖子上套著靴子，
with a boot on their neck,
但儘管如此，還是要繁榮......
but to prosper in spite of it...
我懷疑它的啟發
I suspect it inspired
他內心充滿了撒旦的嫉妒。
satanic jealousy within him.
綜上所述，
In conclusion,
看起來好像
it looks as though
這位女士抗議得太多了。
the lady doth protest too much.
有櫻桃可去嗎
Is there a cherry to go
在這褻瀆的蛋糕上，
on this blasphemous cake,
或者你完成了嗎？
or have you finished?
（笑）
(LAUGHS)
（竊聽）
(TAPPING)
我必須承認，
I must confess,
我不僅尊重
not only do I respect
並欽佩猶太人......
and admire the Jew...
我孤身一人。
I am one.
（緊張的音樂播放）
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
（笑）
(LAUGHING)
-（笑）
- (LAUGHING)
-（緊張的音樂漸漸消失）
- (TENSE MUSIC FADES)
（笑）
(LAUGHING)
瑪喬麗：開玩笑！
MARJORIE: Kidding!
他們是貪吃的老鼠。
They're greedy rats.
我認為這可能是
I think this could be
開始
the beginning
一段美好的友誼。
of a beautiful friendship.
然後我會舉辦一個聚會
Then I shall throw a party
慶祝。
to celebrate.
我不喜歡聚會。
I don't care for parties.
哦，糟蹋了！
Oh, spoilsport!
每個人都喜歡聚會。
Everybody loves a party.
（緊張的西方音樂演奏）
(TENSE WESTERN MUSIC PLAYING)
公爵夫人離開
The Duchessa's leaving
三天前
three days earlier
比我們想像的。
than we thought.
如果我們不告訴
If we don't tell
女僕榮譽，
the Maid Honor,
他們會來得太晚了。
they'll arrive too late.
（模糊不清的喋喋不休）
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
接線員：來了。
OPERATOR: Incoming.
（信號蜂鳴聲）
(SIGNAL BEEPING)
接觸。
Contact.
瑪喬麗：更多傑瑞
MARJORIE: More Jerries
島上的情況比預想的要好。
on the island than expected.
罐頭咸牛肉
Tin of corned beef's
從食品儲藏室出來
out of pantry
提前三天。
three days early.
（信號蜂鳴聲）
(SIGNAL BEEPING)
我會接受的。
I'll take that.
接線員：這是保密的，
OPERATOR: It's confidential,
先生。僅適用於 M。
sir. For M only.
當談到
When it comes
進行提取，
to make the extraction,
它需要是一個非常...
it needs to be a very...
先生。留言，先生。
Sir. Message, sir.
（信號蜂鳴聲）
(SIGNAL BEEPING)
GUS：更多傑瑞
GUS: More Jerries
島上的情況比預想的要好。
on the island than expected.
咸牛肉已經從食品儲藏室裡拿出來了
Corned beef's out of the pantry
提前三天。
three days early.
動作快點。
Move faster.
M：是的，但是增加了
M: Yes, but there's increased
該地區的潛艇目擊事件。
U-boat sightings in the area.
先生。
Sir.
（電話鈴聲）
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
官員：任務的
OFFICER: The mission's
仍在進行中。
still proceeding.
弗雷迪：所以，還有更多
FREDDY: So, there's more
島上的士兵
soldiers on the island
船要提前出發嗎？
and the boat's leaving earlier?
是的。
Yes.
嗯，怎麼樣
Well, how are
我們的意思是要走得更快嗎？
we meant to move faster?
我們不能走得更快。
We can't move faster.
我們會盡可能快地前進。
We're going as fast as we can.
這是一艘漁船，
This is a fishing boat,
這不是快艇。
it's not a speedboat.
M：總理，
M: Prime Minister,
公爵夫人離開
the Duchessa's leaving
12 天後費爾南多·波 (Fernando Po)。
Fernando Po in 12 days.
按照我們目前的時間表，
On our current schedule,
他們會到達
they'll arrive
晚了三天。
three days too late.
還可以做嗎？
Can it still be done?
M：我們還在
M: We're still
等待回復
awaiting a response
來自菲利普斯少校。
from Major Phillips.
如果我們不能走得更快
If we can't move faster,
我們會走得更短。
we'll go shorter.
我們可以去找費爾南多·波
We can get to Fernando Po
12天內。
in 12 days.
堅持住，你說
Hold on, you said
我們不能再短了。
we couldn't go shorter.
不，我說
No, I said
我們不想走得更短。
we don't want to go shorter.
他說我們會得到
He said we'll get
被U型潛艇擊落。
mowed down by a U-boat.
或者更糟糕的是，
Or worse,
被英國人撿到了。
picked up by the Brits.
他們的驅逐艦艦隊
Their armada of destroyers
正在穿越那裡。
are crossing there.
弗雷迪：我們真的會
FREDDY: We will literally
在U型潛艇上航行。
be sailing over U-boats.
抱歉，夥計們，我們走得更短了。
Sorry, lads, we go shorter.
（驚險
(THRILLING
西洋音樂演奏）
WESTERN MUSIC PLAYING)
（飛機引擎隆隆作響）
(AIRPLANES ENGINES RUMBLING)
Drei，zwei，eins...
Drei, zwei, eins...
（繼續說德語）
(CONTINUES SPEAKING GERMAN)
（微弱的爆炸聲）
(FAINT EXPLOSIONS)
（音樂漸強、漸弱）
(MUSIC CRESCENDOES, FADES)
（無聲的爆炸聲）
(MUTED EXPLOSIONS)
（緊張的西方音樂演奏）
(TENSE WESTERN MUSIC PLAYING)
丘吉爾：先生們，
CHURCHILL: Gentlemen,
正如我現在對你所說的那樣，
as I speak to you now,
再次倫敦
London once again
在納粹的統治下不寒而慄
shudders beneath a Nazi
來自天空的猛攻。
onslaught from the skies.
在這樣的時候，
And at such times,
男人的心
the hearts of men
被攪拌去上班。
are stirred to duty.
（通過無線電）
(OVER RADIO)
但你們不是這樣的人。
But you are not such men.
你沒有被選中
You were not chosen
為了你的顯赫榮譽
for your conspicuous honor
或崇高的理想。
or high ideals.
你被選中了
You were chosen
因為你是
because you are
最後的手段。
the last resort.
使命
The mission
你已被給予
you have been given
是某種
is of a sort
以前從未進行過。
never before undertaken.
它需要無情的人，
It demands ruthless men,
誰會毫不猶豫
who will not hesitate
彎下腰
to stoop beneath
戰爭慣例。
the conventions of war.
不保持雙手清潔的男性。
Men who do not keep clean hands.
像你這樣的男人。
Men like you.
-（微弱的爆炸聲）
- (FAINT EXPLOSIONS)
- 然而，誰還在密謀
- And yet, who still conspire
在他們自己的
in their own
不和諧的和諧。
discordant harmony.
誰知道卻不在乎
Who know and yet do not care
他們可能永遠不會回來。
that they may never return.
還有誰繼續前進
And who press onward
不為榮耀，
not for glory,
或者為了職責，或者為了我，
or for duty, or for me,
但是因為你們是男人
but because you are men
誰不會停下來
who will not stop
直到完成。
until it is done.
祝您好運，先生們。
Godspeed, gentlemen.
（緊張的西部音樂繼續）
(TENSE WESTERN MUSIC CONTINUES)
呃……夥計們……
Uh... Chaps...
那是一艘英國驅逐艦。
That's a British destroyer.
我們應該搬家。
We should move.
我們無法超越，先生。
We can't outrun that, sir.
嗯，我們見過他們，
Well, we've seen them,
他們見過我們。
they've seen us.
指揮官：
COMMANDER:
堅持住，女僕榮譽。
Hold fast, Maid Honor.
我們正在準備
We're preparing
登機派對。
a boarding party.
拉森：你好，隊長！
LASSEN: Hello, Captain!
這裡沒什麼令人興奮的。
Nothing exciting here.
我們只是瑞典漁民。
We're just Swedish fishermen.
指揮官：
COMMANDER:
前進吧，喬根森！
Step forward, Jorgensen!
喬根森，你是瑞典人。
Jorgensen, you're Swedish.
問他們在哪裡
Ask them where
他們正在前進，你會嗎？
they're heading, would you?
（說瑞典語）
(SPEAKING SWEDISH)
（瑞典語）
(IN SWEDISH)
（英語）不是你，拉森。
(IN ENGLISH) Not you, Lassen.
呃...
Uh...
我想聽馬奇·菲利普斯
I want to hear March-Phillips
試試吧。
have a go.
啊。
Ah.
很公平。
Fair enough.
遊戲開始了，指揮官。 （笑聲）
Game's up, Commander. (CHUCKLES)
不能責怪一個女孩的嘗試。
Can't blame a girl for trying.
幹得好，少校。
Good effort, Major.
但我擔心你會走
But I'm afraid you are going
必須和我們一起去。
to have to come with us.
請問在誰的授權下
May I ask under whose authority
我們被伏擊了？
we've been waylaid?
根據龐德海軍上將的命令。
On the orders of Admiral Pound.
（雷達脈衝）
(RADAR PINGS)
操作員：中尉。
OPERATOR: First Lieutenant.
你正在追求
You are pursuing
未經批准的
an unsanctioned
犯罪企業
criminal enterprise
在國際水域。
in international waters.
你會引起不安。
You're going to cause an upset.
我覺得我們有點
I think we're a little
過去的不安，指揮官。
past upset, Commander.
史蒂文斯，你有什麼？
Stevens, what have you got?
史蒂文斯：先生，我檢測到了。
STEVENS: I had a ping, sir.
貪婪的小納粹
The greedy little Nazi
不會滿足
won't be satisfied
擁有歐洲大部分地區，
with holding most of Europe,
他在追尋我們自己的
he's after our own
綠色宜人的土地。
green and pleasant land.
好吧，感謝上帝你在這裡
Well, thank God you're here
和你的小
with your little
木製戰艦
wooden battleship
還有你的五人軍隊。
and your five-man army.
-（ping）
- (PINGS)
- U 型潛艇，方位 273。
- U-boat, bearing 273.
- 拉響警報。
- Sound the alarm.
-（警報聲）
- (ALARM BLARING)
上船吧。
Come aboard.
軍官：U 型潛艇正在接近。
OFFICER: U-boat approaching.
右舷一側，長官。
Starboard side, sir.
戰鬥站！
Battle stations!
少校，如果你知道的話
Major, if you know
什麼對你有好處，
what's good for you,
- 你會回家。
- you'll head home.
- 很好，指揮官。
- Very good, Commander.
海西，帶我們走吧
Haysey, get us away
從那個魚雷磁鐵
from that torpedo magnet
盡快。
as quickly as possible.
好的，先生。蘋果，船尾的人。
Aye, sir. Apple, man the stern.
弗雷迪，在主帆上。
Freddy, on the main sail.
拉森到船頭，現在。
Lassen to the bow, now.
解開那個站！
Untie that station!
拉森：是的。
LASSEN: Aye.
亨利：快點，夥計們！
HENRY: Quickly now, lads!
為我們起航，
Hoist that foresail for us,
孩子們，你願意嗎？
will you, boys?
弗雷迪：主帆準備好牽引！
FREDDY: Main sail ready to haul!
（緊張的音樂播放）
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
亨利：好吧，弗雷迪，
HENRY: All right, Freddy,
現在升起主帆！
now raise that main sail!
弗雷迪：是的。
FREDDY: Aye.
-（警報繼續）
- (ALARM CONTINUES)
- 警官：報告測深。
- OFFICER: Report sounding.
- 史蒂文斯：軸承 163。
- STEVENS: Bearing 163.
-（ping）
- (PINGS)
（水手們用德語喊叫）
(SAILORS SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
亨利：（英語）
HENRY: (IN ENGLISH)
拉森，調整主帆
Lassen, trim the main sail
然後把它繫起來！
and then tie it off!
拉森：你對好的事情有什麼期待？
LASSEN: How do you expect good?
史蒂文斯：報告探測。
STEVENS: Report sounding.
軸承115。
Bearing 115.
- 軍官：火力深水炸彈。
- OFFICER: Fire depth charges.
-（ping）
- (PINGS)
（杠桿點擊）
(LEVER CLICKS)
（爆炸聲）
(EXPLOSION BOOMING)
（水手們含糊地喊叫）
(SAILORS SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
（無聲的爆炸聲）
(MUTED EXPLOSIONS)
（警報聲響起）
(ALARM BLARING)
（音樂漸弱）
(MUSIC FADES)
（遠處爆炸）
(DISTANT EXPLOSIONS)
（人們說話含糊不清）
(PEOPLE SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
（有趣的音樂播放）
(INTRIGUING MUSIC PLAYING)
瑪喬麗：所以，這是你的男人
MARJORIE: So, this is your man
能把事情做好嗎？
that gets things done?
他的名字叫坎普·比利……
His name is Kamp Billy...
與 K。
with a K.
他去了
And he went
去英國寄宿學校？
to an English boarding school?
不僅僅是任何寄宿學校。
Not just any boarding school.
他去了伊頓公學，
He went to Eton,
寄宿學校。
the boarding school.
正確的...
Right...
（遠處槍聲）
(DISTANT GUNSHOT)
那他來這裡做什麼？
Then what's he doing here?
他是一位王子。
He's a prince.
到底是什麼王子？
A prince of what, exactly?
- 費爾南多·波王子！
- The Prince of Fernando Po!
-（槍聲）
- (GUNSHOT)
所以，他有一部分是海盜，
So, he's part pirate,
部分貴族？
part aristocrat?
別緻。
Chic.
他也是
He's also
我們解決方案的一部分。
a part of our solution.
相對濕度。
RH.
（音樂漸弱）
(MUSIC FADES)
知識庫。
KB.
他回到城裡了。
He's back in town.
男：長官。
MAN: Chief.
（講約魯巴語的男子）
(MAN SPEAKING YORUBA)
（槍聲）
(GUNSHOT)
（英語）看起來像
(IN ENGLISH) Seems like
你總是帶著禮物來。
you always come bearing gifts.
她是為了我嗎？
Is she for me?
- 祝你好運。
- Good luck with that.
-（輕笑）
- (CHUCKLES)
我不是為了你，
I'm not for you,
但這些是。
but these are.
嗯。好東西。好吃。
Mmm. Goodies. Yummy.
-（男人咕噥）
- (MEN GRUNT)
- （男子說約魯巴語）
- (MAN SPEAKING YORUBA)
-（英語）阿德...
- (IN ENGLISH) Ade...
- 酋長。
- Chief.
阿德達約：來吧，來吧。
ADEDAYO: Come on, come on.
（男人說話含糊不清）
(MEN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
有人有品味。
Someone has taste.
比母雞的牙齒還稀有。
Rarer than hens' teeth.
嗯，RH 告訴我 KB
Well, RH tells me that KB
是唯一可以交談的人
is the only man to talk to
當談到
when it comes
把事情做好。
to getting things done.
為什麼我感覺
Why do I feel like
我已經離開了
I've gone from being
- 捕食者對獵物？
- the predator to the prey?
- (旋塞槍)
- (COCKS GUN)
（槍聲）
(GUNSHOT)
（清嗓子）
(CLEARS THROAT)
相當不錯的入口，年輕的女士。
Quite an entrance, young lady.
是有條件的
It's on the condition
我們對它們進行採樣...
that we sample them...
現在。
now.
艾德，擺桌子。
Ade, set the table.
阿德達約：隊長。
ADEDAYO: Chief.
（笑）
(LAUGHING)
然後公爵說：
And then the Duke said,
「把它推進去，直到它停止為止！」
"Push it in till it stops!"
（大家都笑了）
(ALL LAUGHING)
你真是個武器。
You are quite the weapon.
我是對的，
I was right,
我是獵物。
I was the prey.
我會幫你
I'll help you
因為我不喜歡納粹。
because I don't like Nazis.
不是因為他們是納粹分子
Not because they're Nazis
但因為他們很粗魯。
but because they're gauche.
我給你拉一下
I'll give you a tug
和我最好的12個人，
and 12 of my best men,
包括你真正的。
including yours truly.
但如果我要幫助你的話
But if I'm gonna help you,
誰來幫助我？
who's gonna help me?
因為你是
Because you're
不是士兵，RH。
not a soldier, RH.
不，但她是。
No, but she is.
她會超越你的伴郎。
She'll outshoot your best man.
（吹覆盆子）
(BLOWS RASPBERRY)
（槍聲）
(GUNSHOT)
（旋塞槍）
(COCKS GUN)
（槍聲）
(GUNSHOT)
（旋塞槍）
(COCKS GUN)
（槍聲）
(GUNSHOTS)
（吹）
(BLOWS)
我告訴你了。
I told you.
- 不！
- No!
（神秘的音樂響起）
(MYSTERIOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
瑪喬麗：鸛鳥送來的。查看。
MARJORIE: Stork delivery. Check.
查看。
Check.
二十三個男孩。查看。
Twenty-three boys. Check.
-（信號蜂鳴聲）
- (SIGNAL BEEPING)
- 鸛交付。
- Stork delivery.
二十三個男孩。
Twenty-three boys.
十七個女孩。
Seventeen girls.
集合地點20公里
Meeting point 20 kilometers
費爾南多·波城外。
outside Fernando Po.
與海倫的約會。
The rendezvous with Heron.
你能帶我們去那裡嗎？
Can you get us there?
如果天氣好的話，
If the weather holds,
我可以，先生。
I can, sir.
（神秘的音樂繼續）
(MYSTERIOUS MUSIC CONTINUES)
二十英鎊說
Twenty quid says
這結局並不好。
this doesn't end well.
為了誰？
For who?
對於他們來說。
For them.
你不能把賭注押在自己身上
You can't bet on yourself,
海西。這就是比賽造假。
Haysey. That's match-fixing.
我們開始做吧。
Let's do it.
海倫，好久不見了。
Heron, it's been too long.
很高興見到你，格斯。
Good to see you, Gus.
蘋果。
Apple.
這是坎普比利，
This is Kamp Billy,
費爾南多·波親王。
the Prince of Fernando Po.
殿下。
Your Highness.
他同意幫助我們。
He's agreed to help us.
請原諒我，但是...
Forgive me, but...
我有一種奇特的感覺
I have a peculiar feeling
我們以前見過。
that we've met before.
我對此深有體會。
I get that a lot.
我經常出差。
I'm extremely well-traveled.
（輕笑）不，不。
(CHUCKLES) No, no.
這是一種特殊的感覺。
It's a particular sense.
我不認為
I don't suppose
你打板球，是嗎？
you played cricket, did you?
（笑聲）
(CHUCKLES)
伊頓隊長。 '21 至 '22。
Captained Eton. '21 to '22.
我就知道我認識你的臉！
I knew I knew your face!
下一個
Right next
到獎盃櫃。
to the trophy cabinet.
一個八英尺高
An eight-foot-tall
巨大的肖像。
huge portrait.
是的，正是如此！
Yes, exactly that!
一隻眼睛盯著邊界……
One eye on the boundary...
兩人：……一隻眼睛盯著酒吧。
BOTH: ...one eye on the pub.
非常高興你能加入。
Bloody glad to have you aboard.
坎普比利： 太棒了
KAMP BILLY: Bloody good
來這裡，老男孩。
to be here, old boy.
我感到很無聊
I'm very bored
與這些納粹分子一起
with these Nazis making
他們自己的麻煩。
a nuisance of themselves.
我是說，
I mean,
這對生意來說太糟糕了。
it's terrible for business.
我簡直太高興了
I'm only too pleased
來幫你
to help you
讓他們流鼻血。
serve them a bloody nose.
這是一種值得稱讚的態度。
That's a commendable attitude.
那麼，你的計劃是什麼？
So, what's your plan?
蘋果。
Apple.
本來打算
We're going
沉沒公爵夫人號，
to sink the Duchessa,
加上兩個拖船。
plus the two tugs.
殘害希特勒
Crippling Hitler's
大西洋艦隊的U型潛艇。
Atlantic fleet of U-boats.
非常好。
Very good.
事情是，
The thing is,
我們的老朋友納粹
our old friends the Nazis
並沒有讓它變得最簡單。
aren't making it the easiest.
我們寡不敵眾
We're outnumbered
兩百比五。
two hundred to five.
還有幾個士兵
There's a few more soldiers
比我們預期的。
than we anticipated.
我想我們將會有
I think that we're gonna have
找到我們自己
to find ourselves
還有幾個身材魁梧的小伙子。
a few more strapping lads.
阿德...
Ade...
（約魯巴語）
(SPEAKING YORUBA)
（有趣的
(INTRIGUING
西洋音樂演奏）
WESTERN MUSIC PLAYING)
（英語）對...
(IN ENGLISH) Right...
（咀嚼）
(CHOMPING)
是的，我想這樣就可以了。
Yes, I think that will do.
我們帶了一些武器
We brought some weapons
如果你需要。
if you need.
你抓住那些。
You hold onto those.
我們帶了自己的。
We brought our own.
（約魯巴語）
(SPEAKING YORUBA)
（英語）噢！
(IN ENGLISH) Oyah!
給他們看鐵！
Show them the iron!
（阿德達約講約魯巴語）
(ADEDAYO SPEAKING YORUBA)
（英語）太棒了。
(IN ENGLISH) Marvelous.
坎普比利：你知道
KAMP BILLY: You do know
公爵夫人是
the Duchessa is
超過200英尺
more than 200 feet
從港口一側？
from the harbor side?
而她卻在眾目睽睽之下
And she's in full glare
的燈。
of the lights.
她不會輕易沉沒
She's not gonna be easy to sink
不吸引
without attracting
不必要的關注。
unwanted attention.
是的。這就是為什麼蒼鷺
Yes. That's why Heron
會安放炸彈
will plant a bomb
吹燈，
to blow the lights,
在我們划槳之前
before we paddle in
並安裝船體
and rig the hull
與炸藥。
with explosives.
到......的時候
By the time
炸藥爆炸，
the explosives detonate,
我們要回家了。
we'll be heading home.
如果我按照自己的方式行事的話
If I had it my way,
永遠不會開槍。
a shot'll never be fired.
以及多久一次
And how often
你有辦法嗎？
do you have it your way?
這取決於你問誰，老男孩。
Depends on who you ask, old boy.
（坎普·比利輕笑）
(KAMP BILLY CHUCKLES)
格斯：先生們……
GUS: Gentlemen...
- 阿德。
- Ade.
- 酋長。
- Chief.
- 準備人員。
- Prepare the men.
- （阿德達約說約魯巴語）
- (ADEDAYO SPEAKING YORUBA)
我要那20個
I'll take that 20
只要你準備好，弗雷迪。
whenever you're ready, Freddy.
（含糊其辭的公告
(INDISTINCT ANNOUNCEMENT
揚聲器）
OVER SPEAKERS)
瑪喬麗：公爵夫人
MARJORIE: The Duchessa
到早上就會消失。
will be gone by the morning.
- 你能做到嗎？
- Can you manage that?
-（炸彈點擊）
- (BOMB CLICKING)
它是兩根電線和一個滴答聲。
It's two wires and a tick-tock.
我確信我能應付。
I'm sure I can cope.
你應該不是我
It's not me you should be
擔心。
worried about.
我從來沒有
I've never
帶納粹去參加聚會。
taken a Nazi to a party.
只是不要結束
Just don't end up
在他的一個聚會上。
at one of his parties.
別擔心我。
Don't worry about me.
我將會有
I'm gonna have
我自己的小聚會。
my own little party.
（男人說話含糊不清）
(MEN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
（音樂漸弱）
(MUSIC FADES)
GUS：給孩子們喝一杯，
GUS: Drink for the boys,
關於國王陛下的政府。
on His Majesty's government.
按說，
Ordinarily,
我會咬掉你的手
I'd bite your hand off,
據我所知
as I have been known
喜歡一英鎊紙幣。
to love a pound note.
（約魯巴語）
(SPEAKING YORUBA)
（用英語講）
(IN ENGLISH)
但在這一次，
But on this occasion,
飲料由我來。
the drinks are on me.
然而，
However,
如果國王陛下的政府
if His Majesty's government
正在分發頭銜...
was handing out titles...
你已經是王子了
You're already a prince,
老男孩。
old boy.
那裡有王子
There's Prince
費爾南多·波，但是……
of Fernando Po, but...
王國的騎士
a Knight of the Realm
它有一定的古老性。
has a certain antiquity to it.
起來，坎普·比利爵士。
Arise, Sir Kamp Billy.
你是個好人，格斯。
You're a good man, Gus.
祝你好運，比利。
Good luck, Billy.
（懸疑的音樂播放）
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
（機器呼呼聲）
(MACHINERY WHIRRING)
你好！
Hola!
Buenas tardes，同伴們！
Buenas tardes, companeros!
（點擊）
(CLICKS)
（士兵，德語）
(SOLDIER, IN GERMAN)
（音樂變得戲劇化）
(MUSIC TURNS DRAMATIC)
（在德國）
(IN GERMAN)
（槍聲）
(GUNSHOTS)
(GUN CLICKS)
（尖叫）
(SCREAMING)
-（身體滑動，重擊）
- (BODY SLIDES, THUDS)
-（音樂漸弱）
- (MUSIC FADES)
（炸彈滴答作響）
(BOMB TICKING)
（輕柔的鋼琴曲演奏）
(GENTLE PIANO MUSIC PLAYING)
我的先生，您有訪客。
My Herr, you have a visitor.
噠噠！
Ta-da!
（歌聲）
(IN SING-SONG VOICE)
克利奧帕特拉需要她的凱撒。
Cleopatra needs her Caesar.
穿上。
Put it on.
（哼哼）
(SNORTS)
謝謝你，蒂莫西。
Thank you, Timothy.
一秒。
One second.
蒂莫西...
Timothy...
我有還盤。
I have a counter offer.
讓我們把
Let's put
這打扮放在一邊。
this dressing up aside.
這是給孩子們的。
It's for children.
而且我們不是孩子。
And we are not children.
讓我們舉辦我們自己的派對吧。
Let's make our own party.
一場黑暗的派對。
A dark party.
一個黑暗的納粹黨。
A dark Nazi party.
配合音樂、潤滑
With music, lubrication
還有一個英俊的納粹分子。
and a handsome Nazi.
自從我來到這裡，
Since I've been here,
我被東西咬了
I've been bitten by things
那呱呱叫和滑行的聲音，
that croak and slither,
蝎子在我的靴子裡築巢
scorpions nest in my boots
我無法入睡
and I can't sleep
為了無情的嚎叫
for the relentless howl
叢林熵。
of jungle entropy.
今晚，
Tonight,
我要去參加那個聚會
I'm going to that party,
你正在帶我。
and you are taking me.
現在，穿上它。
Now, put it on.
（卡嚓舌頭）哦。
(CLICKS TONGUE) Oh.
很好。
Very well.
（激動人心的音樂演奏）
(EXCITING MUSIC PLAYING)
（人們說話含糊不清）
(PEOPLE SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
（笑聲）
(LAUGHTER)
女人：啊！ 你好！
WOMAN: Ah! Hola!
燈滅後我們就移動。
We move when the lights go out.
-（女人呼喊）
- (WOMAN WHOOPING)
- （樂隊演奏搖擺樂）
- (BAND PLAYING SWING MUSIC)
（男人笑）
(MAN LAUGHING)
好吧，裡卡多，
All right, Ricardo,
今天你是El Capitan。
today you're El Capitan.
阿曼多，酒吧是你的了。
Armando, the bar is yours.
用它。隨心所欲地濫用它。
Use it. Abuse it at your will.
比內亞：（輕笑）
BINEA: (CHUCKLES)
這就是為什麼我愛你。
That's why I love you.
跟我來吧，帥哥。
Come with me, handsome.
（比內亞說西班牙語）
(BINEA SPEAKING SPANISH)
海倫：我需要你
HERON: I need you
為了讓男人們開心。
to keep the men happy.
多麼高興？
How happy?
（樂隊繼續演奏
(BAND CONTINUES PLAYING
搖擺樂）
SWING MUSIC)
（含糊不清的對話）
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
瑪喬麗：嗯。
MARJORIE: Mmm.
老鼠在窩裡嗎？
Are the rats in the nest?
你找不到德國人
You won't find a German,
西班牙或意大利官員
Spanish or Italian officer
今晚還有其他地方。
anywhere else tonight.
-（搖擺樂繼續）
- (SWING MUSIC CONTINUES)
-（人們歡呼）
- (PEOPLE CHEERING)
HERON：在啤酒節之間
HERON: Between the beer fest
在港口
at the harbor
還有這次小小的聚會，
and this little get-together,
那將是90%的士兵
that'll be 90% of the soldiers
遠離碼頭。
away from the dock.
收費已設定
The charge is set
吹滅港口燈光
to blow the harbor lights
30分鐘後。
in 30 minutes.
你能把他留在這裡這麼久嗎？
Can you keep him here that long?
愚蠢的孩子，愚蠢的問題。
Silly boy, silly question.
看看這件衣服。
Look at the dress.
（男人歡呼）
(MAN CHEERS)
（笑）
(LAUGHS)
（喇叭信號彈）
(TRUMPET FLARES)
你好。
Hi.
所以，你管這叫派對？
So, you call this a party?
瑪喬麗：這只是
MARJORIE: This is just
楔子的薄端。
the thin end of the wedge.
我創作了一場表演
I've created a performance
只為你。
just for you.
好吧，我可以告訴你
Well, I could show you
一個真正的聚會。
a real party.
（瑪喬麗輕笑）
(MARJORIE CHUCKLES)
（用意大利語）
(IN ITALIAN)
（人們歡呼、鼓掌）
(PEOPLE CHEERING, APPLAUDING)
-（笑）
- (LAUGHS)
-（瘋狂的音樂播放）
- (FRANTIC MUSIC PLAYING)
（用意大利語）
(IN ITALIAN)
（用英語講）
(IN ENGLISH)
我為什麼要關心，意大利面？
Why do I care, Spaghetti?
比薩。
Pizza.
打擾一下
Excuse me
當我搽鼻涕的時候。
while I powder my nose.
- 又是什麼？
- What, again?
-（嘲笑）
- (SCOFFS)
別驚慌，凱撒。
Don't panic, Caesar.
溫習一下意大利語。
Brush up on your Italian.
你的禮物需要包裝。
Your gift needs to be wrapped.
留住那些軍官
Keep those officers
請喝酒。
drinking, please.
- 當然。好的。
- Of course. Okay.
- 謝謝你，費米。
- Thank you, Femi.
公爵夫人號的船體
The Duchessa's hull
已得到加強。
has been reinforced.
它不會沉沒。
It won't sink.
我們需要停止任務。
We need to stop the mission.
（瘋狂的音樂繼續）
(FRANTIC MUSIC CONTINUES)
這將很難做到。
That's going to be hard to do.
瑪喬麗：聽我說。
MARJORIE: Listen to me.
我們的使命將會失敗。
Our mission will fail.
炸藥不起作用
The explosives won't work
因為他強化了它
because he's reinforced it
不沉的。
to be unsinkable.
你現在必須阻止他們。
You have to stop them now.
但收費約為
But the charge is about
吹燈。
to blow the lights.
（炸彈滴答作響）
(BOMB TICKING)
好吧，如果你不能
Well, if you can't
停止燈光，
stop the lights,
阻止男人們。
stop the men.
魯爾不能離開這個政黨。
Luhr must not leave this party.
我會讓他忙起來。現在出發。
I'll keep him busy. Go, now.
（音樂響起）
(MUSIC INTENSIFIES)
（音樂漸弱）
(MUSIC FADES)
（樂隊演奏搖擺樂）
(BAND PLAYING SWING MUSIC)
GUS：我們出發了。
GUS: And we're off.
傑弗裡：格斯，等等。
GEOFFREY: Gus, wait.
（緊張的音樂播放）
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
（信號蜂鳴聲）
(SIGNAL BEEPING)
鸛鳥對女僕，
Stork to Maid,
鸛鳥對女僕說，進來吧。
Stork to Maid, come in.
第五頻道。
Channel five.
格斯：（通過無線電）
GUS: (OVER RADIO)
這是女僕。切換到 20。
This is Maid. Switching to 20.
繼續。
Go ahead.
罐頭咸牛肉
Tin of corned beef
無法破解。
can't be cracked.
船不會沉沒。
The ship cannot be sunk.
炸藥會失敗。
Explosives will fail.
這是鸛鳥，先生。
It's Stork, sir.
將他放在開放式揚聲器上。
Put him on open speaker.
HERON：咸牛肉
HERON: Corned beef
無法破解。
can't be cracked.
鸛鳥，這是M。
Stork, this is M.
別介意咸牛肉。
Never mind the corned beef.
就找個辦法吧。
Just find a way.
- 超過。
- Over.
- 英鎊來了，先生。
- Pound incoming, sir.
- HERON：重複...
- HERON: Repeat...
- 把它關掉。
- Switch that off.
-我們必須...
- We must...
-（關閉收音機）
- (TURNS OFF RADIO)
（門打開）
(DOOR OPENS)
立即停止這種行為。
Stop this immediately.
你正在做的事現在結束了
What you are doing ends now,
或你們每一個最後的人
or every last one of you
將受法庭管轄。
will be subject to a tribunal.
明白了嗎？
Is that clear?
我不知道什麼
I don't know what
你說的是，先生。
you're talking about, sir.
是這樣嗎，中士？
Is that correct, Sergeant?
海倫：（通過無線電）
HERON: (OVER RADIO)
堅守陣地。
Hold position.
GUS：要多久，鸛？
GUS: How long, Stork?
- HERON：等待命令。
- HERON: Awaiting orders.
- 給我那個。
- Give me that.
HERON：待命。
HERON: Stand by.
馬奇·菲利普斯，
March-Phillips,
這是龐德海軍上將
this is Admiral Pound
給你一個直接的命令。
giving you a direct order.
立即中止此任務。
Abort this mission now.
（通過揚聲器）
(OVER SPEAKERS)
我會確保
I will make sure that
你們都沒有看到
none of you see
重見天日。
the light of day again.
你將花費
You will spend
你的餘生
the rest of your lives
被鎖起來
locked up
遵照陛下的意願。
at His Majesty's pleasure.
這包括你們所有人。
That includes all of you.
傑弗裡·阿普爾亞德，
Geoffrey Appleyard,
安德斯·拉森，
Anders Lassen,
-弗雷迪·巴茲...
- Freddy Buzz...
- 格斯：對不起……
- GUS: I'm sorry...
...和亨利·海耶斯。
...and Henry Hayes.
不太明白
Can't quite make out
- 你在講些什麼。
- what you're saying.
-（無線電靜電爆裂聲）
- (RADIO STATIC CRACKLING)
再見。
Bye.
- 是……清楚了嗎？
- Is... Is that clear?
-（無線電靜電爆裂聲）
- (RADIO STATIC CRACKLES)
GUS：抱歉？什麼？
GUS: Sorry? What?
我不能...
I can't...
我聽不太清楚。
I can't quite hear you.
（猶豫）
(HESITATES)
GUS：請...滾開。
GUS: Please... fuck off.
（接收器卡噠聲）
(RECEIVER CLATTERS)
您和您的運營
You and your operation
是魯莽的，准將。
are reckless, Brigadier.
我個人會
I will personally
向議會提供建議
advise parliament
有首相
to have the Prime Minister
被免職。
removed from office.
我會關閉你的。
And I am going to shut you down.
收到消息
Message received
響亮而清晰，先生。
loud and clear, sir.
我建議你也
I suggest you also
滾蛋吧，中士。
fuck off, Sergeant.
弗萊明，請聯繫馬奇-菲利普斯。
Fleming, contact March-Phillips.
-（廣播點擊）
- (RADIO CLICKS)
-（靜態爆裂聲）
- (STATIC CRACKLES)
莉莉，來找我吧
Lily, get me
總理熱線電話。
the Prime Minister on hotline.
- 莉莉：馬上，先生。
- LILY: Right away, sir.
- 進來吧，01。
- Come in, 01.
進來吧，收到了嗎？
Come in, do you receive?
（接收器卡噠聲）
(RECEIVER CLATTERS)
（電話鈴聲）
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
- 是的？
- Yes?
- M：總理，
- M: Prime Minister,
我害怕
I'm afraid
我們被發現了。
we've been discovered.
（嘆氣）
(SIGHS)
我們中間有一顆內奸
There was a mole in our midst
和龐德海軍上將
and Admiral Pound
已下令執行任務
has ordered the mission
被中止。
to be aborted.
他想要議會
He wants to have parliament
將你撤職。
remove you from office.
使命必須繼續下去。
The mission must continue.
01，這是基地。超過。
01, this is base. Over.
丘吉爾：告訴龐德
CHURCHILL: Tell Pound
如果他有問題，
if he has a problem,
跟我一起解決這個問題。
to take it up with me.
他知道我住在哪裡。
He knows where I live.
告訴隊員們繼續前進。
Tell the men to press on.
恐怕我們已經輸了
I'm afraid we've lost
所有通訊，先生。
all communication, sir.
必須有
There must be
我們可以做的事情。
something that we can do.
唯一的事情
The only thing
我能做的就是提醒你，
I can do is remind you,
原因
the reason
我們選擇了馬奇-菲利普斯
we chose March-Phillips
是因為
is because
他不服從命令。
he doesn't follow orders.
那麼希望我們選擇得好。
Then let's hope we chose well.
（接收器卡噠聲）
(RECEIVER CLATTERS)
（嘆氣）
(SIGHS)
公爵夫人號的船體
The Duchessa's hull
已得到加強。
has been reinforced.
這意味著她不能沉沒。
Which means she can't be sunk.
至少沒有金額
At least not with the amount
我們攜帶的炸藥。
of explosives we're carrying.
只是想知道如何以及何時
Just wondering how and when
這正是發生的。
exactly this took place.
這並不重要
It's not important
它是如何以及何時發生的。
how and when, it's happened.
嗯，是的
Well, it is
有點重要，格斯。
kind of important, Gus.
我不在乎
I don't care
關於入獄時間，
about the prison time,
但我確實關心完成
but I do care about finishing
我們已經開始的事情。
what we've started.
謝謝你，弗雷迪。
Thank you, Freddy.
必須有
There must be
某種錯誤。
some sort of mistake.
你不能只是強化...
You can't just reinforce...
沒有錯，海西。
There's no mistake, Haysey.
我只是迷失了
I'm just lost about
具體如何以及何時...
how and when exactly...
- 足夠的！
- Enough!
-（桌子發出嘎嘎聲）
- (TABLE RATTLES)
為什麼我們不擊沉拖船呢？
Why don't we sink the tug boats?
擺脫班車
Get rid of the shuttle
到U型潛艇。
to the U-boats.
這不夠。
It's not enough.
他們將在一周內更換它們。
They'll replace them in a week.
我們為什麼不偷它們呢？
Why don't we steal them?
我們可以使用比利的船
We can use Billy's boat
拖動公爵夫人
to drag the Duchessa
出港
out of the harbor
並偷走另外兩個
and steal the other two
德國拖船
German tug boats
為U型潛艇提供服務。
that service the U-boats.
怎麼樣？
And how are
我們應該這樣做嗎？
we supposed to do that?
她不僅是雙盤，
Not only is she double-plated,
重量是原來的兩倍，
weighing twice as much,
但你需要一個完整的工作人員
but you'd need a full crew
移動那麼大的船。
to move a ship that size.
拖船就是船員。
The tug boats are the crew.
我們拖曳公爵夫人
We tow the Duchessa
出海
out to the ocean
然後，好吧，偷很多東西。
and, well, steal the lot.
然後呢？
Then what?
我們仍然無法擊沉它們。
We still can't sink them.
我們不需要。
We don't need to.
我們揚帆起航
We sail
進入國際水域
into international waters
並把一切都交給
and hand everything
交給海軍。
over to the Navy.
無論如何他們都在跟蹤我們
They're following us anyway,
所以他們會非常高興
so they'll be more than happy
再次見到我們。
to see us again.
那麼錨呢？
And what about the anchor?
你見過它的大小嗎？
Have you seen the size of it?
如果我們要
If we're gonna
真正開始感動她，
actually start to move her,
他們的S艇
their S-boats
幾秒鐘內就會抓住我們。
will catch us in seconds.
好吧，你打算做什麼
Well, what are you going to do
和所有的炸藥
with all the explosives
你帶來了嗎，弗雷迪？
you brought, Freddy?
我們將使用它們
We'll use them
起錨。
to blow the anchor.
我們將裝備 S 艇
We'll rig the S-boats
所以他們無法跟隨，
so they can't follow,
操縱燃料儲備
rig the fuel reserve
為U型潛艇提供補給，
that supplies the U-boats,
然後，好吧，炸毀這一切。
and then, well, blow the lot up.
那次燃油爆炸
That fuel explosion's
會帶來
gonna bring
每個人和他們的母親
everyone and their mother
下到港口。
down to the harbor.
傑弗裡：我們設置了保險絲，
GEOFFREY: We set the fuse,
以便燃油堆爆炸
so that the fuel dump blows
一旦我們出了港口。
once we're outside the harbor.
然後我們悄悄溜出去。
Then we sneak out quietly.
不錯。
Not bad.
（笑）它非常貪婪。
(CHUCKLES) It's very greedy.
- 嗯，我進來了。
- Well, I'm in.
- 拉森：嗯，
- LASSEN: Well,
我不會離開，直到我完成為止
I'm not leaving until I have
一桶裝滿納粹之心。
a barrel full of Nazi hearts.
我會做任何事
I'll do whatever
你告訴我怎麼做，先生。
you tell me to do, sir.
先生們，
Gentlemen,
讓我們偷一些船吧。
let's steal some boats.
（格斯嘆氣）
(GUS SIGHS)
原來她是雙盤，
Turns out she's double-plated,
所以改變計劃。
so change of plans.
本來打算
We're going
而是偷船。
to steal the boats instead.
（嘲笑）
(SCOFFS)
這可能嗎？
Is that even possible?
我不太確定。
I'm not entirely sure.
但如果你願意的話
But if you're up for it,
我們也是。
so are we.
你知道這意味著什麼。
And you know what that means.
血多了很多
A lot more blood
還有更多的汗水。
and a lot more sweat.
希望不是我們任何人，
Hopefully not any of ours,
老男孩。
old boy.
我認為我們做不到
I don't think we can do this
沒有你，比利。
without you, Billy.
（坎普·比利嘆息）
(KAMP BILLY SIGHS)
好吧，如果你願意的話，我願意。
Well, I'm up for it if you are.
我想我們會
I think we're gonna
需要你的拖船。
need your tug.
（坎普·比利輕笑）
(KAMP BILLY CHUCKLES)
海西和我會
Haysey and I will
沿著港口漫步
take a stroll along the harbor
並取出
and take out
任何仍在巡邏的士兵。
any soldiers still patrolling.
弗萊迪將帶來
Freddy will bring
他的小艇在周圍
his dinghy around
並照顧S艇。
and take care of the S-boats.
我們將在拖船上與您會面。
We'll meet you by the tug boats.
坎普·比利：那麼公爵夫人呢？
KAMP BILLY: And the Duchessa?
那是蘋果和我。
That's Apple and me.
我們會照顧任何船員
We'll take care of any crew
並吹錨。
and blow the anchor.
傑弗裡：
GEOFFREY:
並摧毀他們的通訊。
And destroy their comms.
沒有把握
Not sure
您將在船上遇到什麼。
what you'll meet on board.
帶走我的頂級男孩
Take my top boy
還有我的另外兩個人。
and two more of my men.
（緊張的音樂播放）
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
先生們，讓我們做好準備吧。
Gentlemen, let's prepare.
?哦，鯊魚，寶貝
? Oh, the shark, babe
? 親愛的，有這樣的牙齒
? Has such teeth, dear
? 他向他們展示了
? And he shows them
珍珠白
pearly white
（人群歡呼）
(CROWD CHEERING)
? 只是一把折刀
? Just a jack-knife
? 有老麥克希斯，親愛的
? Has old MacHeath, dear
? 他把它放在看不見的地方
? And he keeps it out of sight
? 你知道
? You know
當鯊魚咬人時
when that shark bites
? 用他的牙齒，親愛的
? With his teeth, dear
? 猩紅的巨浪
? Scarlet billows
開始蔓延
starts to spread
? 漂亮的手套，哦，
? Fancy gloves, oh,
親愛的，穿著舊麥克希斯的衣服
wears old MacHeath, dear
? 所以從來沒有，
? So there's never,
沒有一絲紅色
never a trace of red
? 在人行道上
? On the sidewalk
? 週日早上，
? On Sunday morning,
你不知道嗎
don't you know
? 躺著一具屍體
? Lies a body
? 滲出生命
? Oozing life
? 有人偷偷摸摸
? And someone sneakin'
就在拐角處
around the corner
? 難道是這樣嗎
? Could that be
老麥克刀？
old Mack the Knife?
? 有一艘拖船
? There's a tug boat
? 在河邊，
? Down by the river,
你不知道
don't cha know
（呼氣）
(EXHALES)
? 水泥袋的地方
? Where a cement bag's
只是一個-下垂...
just a-drooping on down...
-（歌聲漸弱）
- (SONG FADES)
-（緊張的宏大音樂演奏）
- (TENSE GRAND MUSIC PLAYING)
（船舶馬達的呼呼聲）
(SHIP MOTOR WHIRRING)
（槍聲安靜）
(GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
（水手們用德語說話）
(SAILORS SPEAKING IN GERMAN)
（沙沙聲）
(RUSTLING)
-（槍聲安靜）
- (GUN FIRES QUIETLY)
-（咕嚕聲）
- (GRUNTS)
（士兵含糊其辭）
(SOLDIER SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
還沒有。
Not yet.
（士兵們清嗓子，
(SOLDIERS CLEARING THROAT,
吵鬧）
CLAMORING)
我的先生。
Mein Herr.
（在德國）
(IN GERMAN)
海西...
Haysey...
（槍聲安靜）
(GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
（格斯笑）
(GUS LAUGHING)
（用德語唱歌）
(SINGING IN GERMAN)
（人群喘息、歡呼）
(CROWD GASPS, CHEERS)
（緊張的宏大音樂漸強）
(TENSE GRAND MUSIC CRESCENDOES)
-（音樂漸弱）
- (MUSIC FADES)
-（歌聲繼續低聲）
- (SINGING CONTINUES MUTEDLY)
（用德語發言）
(SPEAKING IN GERMAN)
（激烈的音樂演奏）
(INTENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
亨利：（用英語）在上面
HENRY: (IN ENGLISH) Up there
在左邊，先生。
on the left, sir.
格斯：是的。
GUS: Yes.
-（槍聲安靜）
- (GUN FIRES QUIETLY)
-（士兵尖叫聲）
- (SOLDIER SCREAMS)
-（崩潰）
- (CRASHES)
-（格斯笑）
- (GUS LAUGHS)
他撞車了！
He made a crash!
（士兵含糊不清地喊叫）
(SOLDIER SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
（說德語）
(SPEAKS GERMAN)
-（槍聲安靜）
- (GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
-（士兵們呻吟）
- (SOLDIERS GROAN)
-（士兵用德語喊叫）
- (SOLDIER SHOUTS IN GERMAN)
-（槍聲安靜）
- (GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
我們可以乘坐那輛車，先生。
We could take that car, sir.
為我們節省一些鞋革。
Save us some shoe leather.
（咕嚕聲）
(GRUNTS)
（繼續唱歌）
(CONTINUES SINGING)
（激烈的音樂繼續）
(INTENSE MUSIC CONTINUES)
（低聲歌唱）
(SINGING MUTEDLY)
（可聽到英語）
(AUDIBLY IN ENGLISH)
? 小心，老麥基回來了 ?
? Look out, old Macky is back ?
-（音樂停止）
- (MUSIC STOPS)
-（模糊的對話）
- (INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
（在德國）
(IN GERMAN)
-（槍聲安靜）
- (GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
-（轟鳴聲）
- (THUD)
（車輛接近）
(VEHICLE APPROACHING)
男士：（用英語）來了。
MAN: (IN ENGLISH) Incoming.
（發動機停止）
(ENGINE STOPS)
（門打開、關閉）
(DOORS OPEN, CLOSE)
（腳步聲靠近）
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
請提供論文。
Papers please.
- 指揮官。 （呼氣）
- Commander. (EXHALES)
- 一切都好嗎，弗雷迪？
- All good, Freddy?
收費已定
Charges are set to go
一旦我們出去
once we're out
港口的，先生。
of the harbor, sir.
那我們繼續吧。
Let's carry on then.
（戲劇性的和弦演奏）
(DRAMATIC CHORD PLAYS)
（士兵們含糊其辭）
(SOLDIERS SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
（傑弗裡呼氣）
(GEOFFREY EXHALES)
（海因裡希說德語）
(HEINRICH SPEAKING GERMAN)
瑪喬麗：
MARJORIE:
你喜歡你的禮物嗎？
Did you enjoy your gift?
海因裡希：嗯。
HEINRICH: Mmm.
我想現在是時候了
I think now it's time
狐貍露出了他的巢穴
that the fox shows his den
到狐貍精。
to the vixen.
（緊張的音樂繼續）
(TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES)
-（格斯咕嚕聲）
- (GUS GRUNTS)
-（槍聲安靜）
- (GUN FIRES QUIETLY)
（士兵重擊）
(SOLDIER THUDS)
-（窒息）
- (CHOKING)
-（格斯咕嚕聲）
- (GUS GRUNTS)
-（士兵們歡呼、大笑）
- (SOLDIERS CHEERING, LAUGHING)
-（歡快的音樂播放）
- (UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
蒼鷺，為什麼
Heron, why are
燈還亮著嗎？
the lights still on?
我用油燈照亮房間，
I lit the room with oil lamps,
所以他們不會注意到
so they wouldn't notice
當停電時。
when the power went out.
（人們歡呼、大笑）
(PEOPLE CHEERING, LAUGHING)
（鎖定點擊）
(LOCK CLICKS)
（尖叫聲）
(SCREAMS)
-（水手用德語喊叫）
- (SAILOR SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
- （箭頭呼嘯）
- (ARROW SWOOSHING)
-（水手用德語喊叫）
- (SAILOR SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
-（槍聲）
- (GUNSHOTS)
（傑弗裡氣喘吁吁）
(GEOFFREY PANTING)
（手榴彈碰撞聲）
(GRENADE CLATTERS)
-（警報聲）
- (ALARM BLARING)
-（水手們大聲叫嚷）
- (SAILORS CLAMORING)
-（槍聲）
- (GUNSHOTS)
-（水手們尖叫）
- (SAILORS SCREAM)
- 小心！
- Look out!
-（槍聲）
- (GUNSHOTS)
（槍聲安靜）
(GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
-（尖叫聲）
- (SCREAMS)
-（水手們大聲叫嚷）
- (SAILORS CLAMORING)
（水手大喊）
(SAILOR YELLS)
-（槍聲安靜）
- (GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
-（士兵呻吟聲）
- (SOLDIER GROANS)
弗雷迪，裝備這 88，
Freddy, rig this 88,
然後進行第一次拖船
then take the first tug
與海西。
with Haysey.
- 晚上。
- Gute nacht.
- 古騰阿卜德。
- Guten abend.
（士兵 1 呻吟）
(SOLDIER 1 GROANING)
GUS：Guten 異常結束。
GUS: Guten abend.
-（槍聲安靜）
- (GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
-（士兵 2 尖叫）
- (SOLDIER 2 SCREAMS)
- （說德語）
- (SPEAKS GERMAN)
-（兩人都咕噥著）
- (BOTH GRUNTING)
-（槍聲安靜）
- (GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
-（水手 1 尖叫聲）
- (SAILOR 1 SCREAMS)
（窒息）
(CHOKING)
格斯：（英語）
GUS: (IN ENGLISH)
非常抱歉，老男孩。
Terribly sorry, old boy.
- 你介意嗎？我好像...
- Do you mind? I seem to...
-（刀子叮噹聲）
- (KNIFE CLANGS)
-（扼流圈）
- (CHOKES)
- ...我的刀放錯地方了。
- ...have misplaced my knife.
（呻吟聲）
(GROANS)
（警報繼續響起）
(ALARM CONTINUES BLARING)
（窒息）
(CHOKING)
（拉森咕嚕聲）
(LASSEN GRUNTING)
（水手用德語大喊）
(SAILOR YELLING IN GERMAN)
（呻吟聲）
(GROANS)
-（槍聲）
- (GUNSHOTS)
-（阿德達約尖叫聲）
- (ADEDAYO SCREAMS)
（槍聲安靜）
(GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
-（水手 1 說德語）
- (SAILOR 1 SPEAKING GERMAN)
-（阿德達約大喊）
- (ADEDAYO YELLS)
（水手 2 咕噥著）
(SAILOR 2 GRUNTING)
-（水手 3 喊叫）
- (SAILOR 3 YELLS)
-（水手 4 喘息）
- (SAILOR 4 GASPS)
（水手 5 喊叫
(SAILOR 5 SHOUTS
德語，呻吟聲）
IN GERMAN, GROANS)
（水手 6 喊叫）
(SAILOR 6 YELLS)
（咕嚕聲）
(GRUNTING)
（水手 7 用德語喊叫）
(SAILOR 7 SHOUTS IN GERMAN)
（扼流圈）
(CHOKES)
（緊張的音樂繼續）
(TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES)
-（水手說德語）
- (SAILOR SPEAKS GERMAN)
-（槍聲安靜）
- (GUN FIRES QUIETLY)
-（用德語叫嚷）
- (CLAMORING IN GERMAN)
-（槍聲安靜）
- (GUN FIRES QUIETLY)
（水手 1 咕嚕聲）
(SAILOR 1 GRUNTS)
（水手 2 喊叫）
(SAILOR 2 YELLING)
-（水手 3 尖叫）
- (SAILOR 3 SCREAMING)
-（猛擊）
- (SLASHING)
-（用德語大喊）
- (SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
-（槍聲安靜）
- (GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
-（槍聲）
- (GUNSHOT)
- 混蛋！
- Bugger!
（吵鬧）
(CLAMORING)
謝謝你，比利。
Thank you, Billy.
（兩人都喊叫）
(BOTH SHOUTING)
（水手們講德語）
(SAILORS SPEAKING GERMAN)
- 哦！
- Oh!
-（拉森咕噥）
- (LASSEN GRUNTS)
（水手 1 用德語喊叫）
(SAILOR 1 SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
（尖叫，喘氣）
(SCREAMING, GASPING)
（水手 2 喊叫）
(SAILOR 2 YELLING)
（水手 3 咆哮）
(SAILOR 3 ROARS)
（喘氣）
(GASPING)
-（重擊聲）
- (THUDS)
-（氣喘吁吁）
- (PANTING)
（微弱的叫喊聲）
(FAINT CLAMORING)
（刀子叮噹作響）
(KNIFE CLANGS)
（緊張的音樂繼續）
(TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES)
（兩人都咕噥著）
(BOTH GRUNTING)
（阿德達約大喊，咕噥）
(ADEDAYO YELLS, GRUNTS)
（咕噥，大喊）
(GRUNTING, YELLING)
（音樂漸弱）
(MUSIC FADES)
（敲門聲）
(DOOR CLICKS)
我希望那是
I hope that's
不是你的血，拉森。
not your blood, Lassen.
我也這樣希望。
I hope so too.
（士兵們用德語喊叫）
(SOLDIERS CLAMORING IN GERMAN)
-（槍聲安靜）
- (GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
-（水手們呻吟，重重）
- (SAILORS GROAN, THUD)
（男人咕噥）
(MAN GRUNTS)
好吧，孩子們，放棄吧。
Okay, boys, cast off.
我們讓這艘船離開這裡吧。
Let's get this ship out of here.
（格斯嘆氣）
(GUS SIGHS)
（英語）繼續。繼續...
(IN ENGLISH) Go on. Go on...
繼續！
Go on!
拉森：有三個
LASSEN: There's three
還有更多像這個這樣的房間。
more rooms just like this one.
這應該能阻止U型潛艇
That should stop the U-boats
在接下來的六個月裡。
for the next six months.
讓我們得到這個東西
Let's get this thing
被拖離這裡。
towed out of here.
NDULUE：我們在這裡，孩子們。
NDULUE: We are here, boys.
悄悄。讓我們設置一個警告。
Quietly. Let's set a warning.
我需要你走
I need you to go
到船的前面
to the front of the boat
並連接Vulcan
and attach the Vulcan
致公爵夫人，
to the Duchessa,
拉森和我
Lassen and I
將前往橋。
will head to the bridge.
好的。 （約魯巴語）
Okay. (SPEAKING YORUBA)
（用英語講）
(IN ENGLISH)
走右邊。
Take the right side.
還有你，站起來
And you, get up there
並開始這件事。
and get this thing started.
是格斯。
It's Gus.
傑弗裡：大家都就位了。
GEOFFREY: Everyone's in place.
什麼，
What,
你實際上並沒有想到
you didn't actually think
它會起作用，是嗎？
it would work, did you?
這是你的計劃。
It was your plan.
好吧，讓我們確定一下
Well, let's make sure
我們信守諾言。
we keep our end of the bargain.
回信號，我就出發。
Signal back and I'll heave off.
那麼，現在會發生什麼？
So, what happens now?
我們等待
We wait for
錨鏈被吹。
the anchor chain to blow.
什麼時候
When do
我們預計會發生這種情況嗎？
we expect that to happen?
-（電機呼呼聲）
- (MOTOR WHIRRING)
- 很快，我希望。
- Shortly, I hope.
然後我們就可以帶她去了。
And then we're free to take her.
然而真正的比賽才開始
However, the real race begins
一旦燃料庫消失。
once the fuel depot goes.
然後我們將擁有每一個士兵
Then we'll have every soldier
在島上出現。
on the island turning up.
我們不想
We don't wanna
見證這一點。
be around to witness that.
那個保險絲有多長
How long was that fuse
你附加了
you attached
到錨鏈？
to the anchor chain?
我們很快就會知道。
We'll find out soon enough.
（警報聲微弱）
(ALARM BLARING FAINTLY)
阿德達約：等等，
ADEDAYO: Wait for it,
你會抓住繩子的。
you're gonna catch the rope.
（約魯巴語中男人的叫囂）
(MEN CLAMORING IN YORUBA)
（咕嚕聲）
(GRUNTING)
（戲劇性的和弦演奏）
(DRAMATIC CHORD PLAYS)
（英語）來吧。
(IN ENGLISH) Come on.
（呼呼聲、卡噠聲）
(WHIRS, CLICKS)
-（微弱的爆炸聲）
- (FAINT EXPLOSION)
-（人們倒吸一口涼氣）
- (PEOPLE GASP)
（吵鬧）
(CLAMORING)
（鎖發出嘎嘎聲）
(LOCK RATTLING)
（樂隊演奏搖擺樂）
(BAND PLAYING SWING MUSIC)
第一張多米諾骨牌倒下。
First domino falls.
- 搭上另一條線。
- Hitch up the other line.
- 是的，老闆。
- Yes, boss.
收拾殘局。
Pick up the slack.
弗雷迪：他們需要移動她
FREDDY: They need to move her
在燃油堆爆炸之前。
before the fuel dump blows.
海倫，我們需要瑪喬麗。
Heron, we need Marjorie.
把瑪喬麗交給我吧。
Leave Marjorie to me.
我們會追上你的。
We'll catch you up.
非常好。
Very good.
我們走吧！
Let's go!
（音樂漸弱）
(MUSIC FADES)
（懸疑的音樂播放）
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
海因裡希：
HEINRICH:
我不得不說，小姐，
I have to say, Fraulein,
你很好。
you were good.
而你很狡猾。
And you were sly.
只有
There are only
兩種人
two types of people
像狐貍一樣狡猾。
that are as sly as the fox.
德國人
The German
還有猶太人。
and the Jew.
而且你不是德國人。
And you are not German.
我想現在是時候了...
I think now it's time...
（音樂構建）
(MUSIC BUILDS)
- ...真正的聚會。
- ...for a real party.
-（輕擊聲）
- (LIGHTER CLICKS)
（音樂漸弱）
(MUSIC FADES)
那不是
That wasn't
應該會發生。
supposed to happen yet.
-（微弱的爆炸聲）
- (FAINT EXPLOSIONS)
-（鏈條嘎嘎作響）
- (CHAINS RATTLING)
束縛她！
Shackle her!
並跟隨我。
And follow me.
（含糊不清地喊叫）
(SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
港口遭到攻擊！
The harbor is under attack!
（講西班牙語）
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
（所有人都在叫嚷）
(ALL CLAMORING)
（激烈的西部音樂演奏）
(INTENSE WESTERN MUSIC PLAYING)
（BINEA 德語）
(BINEA IN GERMAN)
（吵鬧）
(CLAMORING)
（警報聲）
(ALARM WAILING)
（微弱的喊叫）
(FAINT SHOUTING)
格斯：他們來了。
GUS: They're coming.
我們需要為發動機提供動力。
We need power on the engine.
（發動機加速）
(ENGINE ACCELERATING)
-她太重了！
- She's too heavy!
- 收拾殘局！
- Pick up the slack!
（咕嚕聲）
(GRUNTS)
（用德語喊叫）
(SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
（旋塞槍）
(COCKS GUN)
GUS：（用英語）等等……
GUS: (IN ENGLISH) Wait...
（德語：士兵 1）
(SOLDIER 1 IN GERMAN)
（士兵 2 喊叫
(SOLDIER 2 SHOUTING
模糊不清）
INDISTINCTLY)
弗雷迪：（英語）
FREDDY: (IN ENGLISH)
她沒動！
She's not moving!
士兵3：開火！火！火！
SOLDIER 3: Fire! Fire! Fire!
格斯：等等。
GUS: Wait for it.
（槍聲）
(GUNSHOTS)
（吵鬧）
(CLAMORING)
-（槍聲安靜）
- (GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
-（喘氣）
- (GASPS)
（士兵們尖叫）
(SOLDIERS SCREAMING)
（士兵 4 含糊不清地喊道）
(SOLDIER 4 SHOUTS INDISTINCTLY)
（士兵 5 喊叫）
(SOLDIER 5 YELLS)
我們需要
We need
為發動機提供更多動力。
more power on the engine.
給我更多的力量！更多力量！
Give me more power! More power!
（發動機加速更猛烈）
(ENGINE ACCELERATES HARDER)
就是這樣，它正在工作！
That's it, it's working!
-（發動機脈衝）
- (ENGINE PULSES)
- 就是這樣！
- That's it!
（冒險的
(ADVENTUROUS
西洋音樂演奏）
WESTERN MUSIC PLAYING)
（官員用德語）
(OFFICER IN GERMAN)
-（叫嚷聲仍在繼續）
- (CLAMORING CONTINUES)
-（槍聲）
- (GUNSHOTS)
（大喊）
(YELLING)
（士兵尖叫）
(SOLDIER SCREAMING)
NDULUE：（英語）準備好了！
NDULUE: (IN ENGLISH) Ready!
（機槍射擊）
(MACHINE GUN FIRING)
（士兵們尖叫）
(SOLDIERS SCREAMING)
-（兩人都咕噥著）
- (BOTH GRUNTING)
-（槍聲）
- (GUN FIRES)
（士兵尖叫）
(SOLDIER SCREAMING)
（尖叫聲）
(SCREAMS)
-（口型）海西！
- (MOUTHING) Haysey!
-（緊張的音樂樓）
- (TENSE MUSIC BUILDING)
-（爆炸）
- (EXPLOSION)
-（尖叫）
- (SCREAM)
（士兵們大聲叫喊）
(SOLDIERS CLAMORING)
（官員用德語）
(OFFICER IN GERMAN)
（音樂放慢）
(MUSIC SLOWS)
（微弱的叫喊聲）
(FAINT CLAMORING)
（用英語講）
(IN ENGLISH)
我們現在已經超出範圍了。
We're out of range now.
- 我不是專家。
- I'm no expert.
-（亨利呻吟）
- (HENRY GROANING)
但你有一個大洞
But you've got a big old hole
在你的肩膀上，海西。
in your shoulder, Haysey.
（士兵們含糊地喊叫）
(SOLDIERS SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
（德語）
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
-（槍聲安靜）
- (GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
-（士兵們呻吟）
- (SOLDIERS GROAN)
（士兵們大聲叫喊）
(SOLDIERS CLAMORING)
（警官用德語喊叫）
(OFFICER SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
（士兵們含糊地喊叫）
(SOLDIERS SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
（官員用西班牙語）
(OFFICER IN SPANISH)
（英語）船長，
(IN ENGLISH) Captain,
你能向我解釋一下嗎
would you explain to me
這裡發生了什麼？
what's going on here?
電源沒了。
The power is gone.
燃料庫
The fuel depot
已被破壞。
has been sabotaged.
並且沒有人知道
And no one knows
發生了什麼。
what's happening.
但這是你的錯。
But this is your fault.
我的船在哪裡？
Where is my ship?
公爵夫人，它去了哪裡？
The Duchessa, where did it go?
有人帶走了他
Someone's taken him
當你不看的時候。
while you weren't looking.
你個傻冒！
You idiot!
你總是必須說些什麼
You always have to say something
在非常錯誤的時間。
at the very wrong time.
從來沒有
There is never
和你一起度過一個合適的時光！
a right time with you!
你的貪婪和變態
Your greed and perversion
分散了你的注意力
has distracted you
來自你的職責。
from your duties.
現在我的港口被毀了。
Now my harbor is destroyed.
我的船也不見了！
And my ship is gone!
而現在你也走了。
And now you're gone too.
謝謝。
Thank you.
（德語）
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
（爆炸）
(EXPLOSION)
（緊張的音樂響起）
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYS)
（英語）令人印象深刻。
(IN ENGLISH) Impressive.
亨利：聽起來像
HENRY: Sounds like
你的雷管起作用了。
your detonators worked.
（兩人都笑）
(BOTH LAUGHING)
（嘆氣）
(SIGHS)
（微弱的叫喊聲）
(FAINT CLAMORING)
（緊張的音樂繼續）
(TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES)
（軍官說德語）
(OFFICER SPEAKS GERMAN)
（士兵們含糊地喊叫）
(SOLDIERS SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
（音樂淡出）
(MUSIC FADES OUT)
起首，小姐。
Chapeau, mademoiselle.
（英語）你打得很好。
(IN ENGLISH) You play well.
你果然是狐貍精啊。
You really are the vixen.
我是嗎？
Am I?
嗯，我的手已經露出來了。
Well, my hand's been revealed.
所以現在怎麼辦？
So, what now?
現在，我握著你的手
Now, I possess your hand
和對於一切
and for everything
你對我所做的事，
you have done to me,
我會參觀
I will visit
千倍地壓在你身上。
a thousand fold upon you.
（在德國）
(IN GERMAN)
（鐵鏈叮噹作響）
(CHAINS CLANG)
（英語）是的。
(IN ENGLISH) Yeah.
（旋塞槍）
(COCKS GUN)
但不是。
But no.
-（士兵喊叫）
- (SOLDIER SHOUTS)
-（槍聲安靜）
- (GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
-（門打開）
- (DOOR OPENS)
- 躺。
- Lie down.
格斯，我們不能等太久了。
Gus, we can't wait much longer.
他們來了。
They're coming.
如果我們留在這裡，
If we stay here,
我們會失去聯繫
we'll lose contact
與其他人。
with the others.
堅持住，比利。
Hold fast, Billy.
蒼鷺有一種生存之道
Heron has a way of surviving
還有瑪喬麗，
and Marjorie,
好吧...祝你好運。
well... good luck with that.
這是一艘巡邏艇
That's a patrol boat
向我們走來。
coming towards us.
- 格斯，我們需要離開。現在。
- Gus, we need to leave. Now.
- (旋塞槍)
- (COCKS GUN)
堅持，稍等...
Hold on...
（船靠近）
(BOAT APPROACHING)
是他們。
It's them.
坎普·比利： RH。
KAMP BILLY: RH.
- KB。
- KB.
- GUS：瑪喬麗。
- GUS: Marjorie.
穿得太過分和穿得太過分
Overdressed and underdressed
同時。
at the same time.
來吧，讓我們來接你
Come on, let's get you
擺脫那些束縛。
out of those shackles.
（靜電爆裂聲）
(STATIC CRACKLING)
進來吧，紫羅蘭。
Come in, Violet.
呼叫紫羅蘭號戰列艦。
Calling H.M.S. Violet.
進來，紫羅蘭。
Come in, Violet.
傑弗裡：（廣播）
GEOFFREY: (ON RADIO)
這是女僕榮譽。
This is Maid Honor.
來吧，女僕榮譽。
Go ahead, Maid Honor.
- 揚聲器。
- Loudspeaker.
-（點擊）
- (CLICKS)
傑弗裡：很抱歉打擾您
GEOFFREY: Sorry to bother you
在深夜的這個時候，
at this time of the night,
但我們發現自己
but we've found ourselves
與一兩個項目
with one or two items
那可能是
that might be
您感興趣。
of interest to you.
我們可以見面嗎
Shall we rendezvous
交接？
for a handover?
給我龐德上將。
Get me Admiral Pound.
（緊張的冒險
(TENSE ADVENTUROUS
音樂播放）
MUSIC PLAYING)
（電話鈴聲）
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
- 是的？
- Yes?
- 古賓斯：（電話）先生，
- GUBBINS: (OH PHONE) Sir,
- 好消息和壞消息。
- good news and bad news.
- 是的是的。開始吧。
- Yes, yes. Get to it.
壞消息，他們沒有擊沉她。
Bad news, they didn't sink her.
好消息，
Good news,
他們偷走了她。
they stole her.
恭喜你，首相。
Congratulations, Prime Minister.
（緊張的冒險
(TENSE ADVENTUROUS
音樂繼續）
MUSIC CONTINUES)
（音樂淡出）
(MUSIC FADES OUT)
（男人們含糊不清地喊叫）
(MEN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
官員： 拿著它！
OFFICER: Hold it there!
指揮官。
Commander.
你被命令了
You were ordered
作者：龐德海軍上將
by Admiral Pound
停止活動。
to cease activities.
你沒有。
You did not.
因此，你是
Therefore, you are
將返回英國
to be returned to England
面對法庭。你。
to face a tribunal. You.
返回您的拖船
Return to your tug
和你的其他民兵一起。
with the rest of your militia.
- 帶他們去雙桅船。
- Take them to the brig.
- 軍官：先生！
- OFFICER: Sir!
我也很高興見到你，指揮官。
Good to see you too, Commander.
分離細胞。
Separate cells.
官員：跟我來！
OFFICER: Follow me!
我們走吧！讓我們行動起來吧！
Let's go! Let's get moving!
- 右手。
- RH.
- KB。
- KB.
水手：來吧。
SAILOR: Come on.
繼續，移動。
Go on, move.
等一下，海員。
One moment, seaman.
（好奇的西方音樂演奏）
(CURIOUS WESTERN MUSIC PLAYING)
比利.
Billy.
一隻眼睛盯著邊界……
One eye on the boundary...
一隻眼睛盯著酒吧。
One eye on the pub.
他們會感謝你的
They'll thank you
為了這一天。
for this one day.
我不知道
I'm not sure
我們就是這樣
that's what we were
真的在尋找，是嗎，
really looking for, was it,
殿下？
Your Highness?
商店開門了
Shop's open
隨時為您服務，少校。
for you anytime, Major.
格洛麗亞：抱歉打擾，
GLORIA: Sorry to intrude,
總理，
Prime Minister,
但M認為
but M thought
你應該看到這個。
you should see this.
丘吉爾：謝謝你，格洛麗亞。
CHURCHILL: Thank you, Gloria.
（音樂變得快樂）
(MUSIC TURNS HAPPY)
（男子含糊不清地喊叫）
(MAN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
-（門嘎嘎作響）
- (GATE RATTLING)
- 警衛：排隊。正面！
- GUARD: Line up. Face front!
排隊。正面！
Line up. Face front!
無需喊叫。
No need to shout.
警衛：站住！
GUARD: Stand still!
有機會喝杯茶嗎？
Any chance of a cup of tea?
你，背靠牆吧。
You, back up to the wall.
掉布，飛蛾。
Off the cloth, moth.
警衛：站直！
GUARD: Stand straight!
（門打開）
(DOOR OPENS)
-（腳步聲接近）
- (FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
-（手杖卡噠作響）
- (WALKING STICK CLACKING)
丘吉爾：以前從未有過
CHURCHILL: Never before
擁有高級軍事
have the senior Military
和海軍指揮官
and Navy Commanders
這個國家的
of this country
如此團結
been so united
在他們的譴責中。
in their condemnation.
這是他們的觀點
It is their view
紀律
that the discipline
其上
on which
我們的武裝部隊取決於
our armed forces depends
已被破壞
has been undermined
不為主人服務的人
by men serving no master
但他們自己的渴求
but their own thirst
流血、謀殺和混亂。
for blood, murder and mayhem.
不服從直接命令的人
Men who disobeyed a direct order
來自海軍上將
from the Admiral
艦隊本身，
of the fleet himself,
並選擇了
and chose instead
相信突發奇想和直覺
to trust the whim and intuition
站在他身邊的那個男人。
of the man standing beside him.
他們怎麼敢。
How dare they.
就在今天早上，
When only this morning,
第一批美國士兵
the first American soldiers
抵達英國土地，
arrived on British soil,
準備站立
ready to stand
並肩
shoulder to shoulder
和我們一起在歐洲。
with us in Europe.
冒著死亡危險的盟友
Allies who risked death
橫渡北大西洋，
crossing the North Atlantic,
只有奇跡
and only by some miracle
找到了他們的十字路口
found their crossing
不受納粹潛艇的困擾。
untroubled by Nazi U-boats.
幸福的境遇，
A happy circumstance,
我可能會補充一點，
I might add,
無法解釋的，
which cannot be accounted for,
但這已經掃清了道路
but which has cleared the way
對於美國
for the United States
進入歐洲戰爭。
to enter the European war.
我知道為此
And for which I know
羅斯福總統
President Roosevelt
表示無限的感激。
to be immeasurably grateful.
但拋開
But setting aside
這一劃
this stroke
無法解釋的財富，
of unexplained fortune,
什麼是要做
what is to be done
和這個不守規矩的公司
with this unruly company
誰不服從命令？
who do not obey orders?
誰似乎已經形成
Who seem to have formed
他們自己的事工
their own ministry
不紳士的戰爭。
of ungentlemanly warfare.
（好奇的西方音樂演奏）
(CURIOUS WESTERN MUSIC PLAYING)
從現在開始，他們為我工作。
From now on, they work for me.
（音樂變得異想天開）
(MUSIC TURNS WHIMSICAL)
（音樂淡出）
(MUSIC FADES OUT)
（迷人的音樂播放）
(CAPTIVATING MUSIC PLAYING)
（有趣的西方音樂演奏）
(AMUSING WESTERN MUSIC PLAYING)
（音樂淡出）
(MUSIC FADES OUT)
（激動人心的音樂演奏）
(EXCITING MUSIC PLAYING)
（激動人心的音樂繼續）
(EXCITING MUSIC CONTINUES)
（緊張的音樂播放）
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
（播放著好奇的輕柔音樂）
(CURIOUS GENTLE MUSIC PLAYING)
（音樂淡出）
(MUSIC FADES OUT)